稳住 别松手
Okay. Hold on. Don't shoot.
瞄准了吗
You see where you're going?
好 现在帮你调整一下姿势
Okay Now let's worry about how you get there.
脚挪过来点 脚尖朝这边
Come a little forward here, Point your toe this way.
转过来一点
Hips, here. Okay?
- 看得见吗 - 嗯
- Can you see? - Yeah.
确定吗
You sure?
- 那这样呢 还看得见吗 - 看不见
- How about now? can you see now? - No…
那这样呢
How about now?
好啦
All right.
准备好了吗 拉弓
Ready? your fingers.
漂亮
Nice!
好球 小屁孩 接着
Nice throw, kiddo! here you go.
你们想加蛋黄酱还是芥末酱 还是都要
Hey, you guys want mayo or mustard, or both?
谁吃热狗加蛋黄酱啊
Who wants mayo on a hotdog?
也许你的弟弟们想要呢 两个芥末酱的 谢啦 孩儿他妈
Pardon your brothers. Two mustards, please! thanks, momma.
没问题
Got it.
奈特 蛋黄还是芥末
Nate, mayo or mustard?
- 我想要番茄酱 - 没问题 我们也带了
- I want ketchup. - Ketchup? We get ketchup too.
注意肘部位置
Mind your elbow…
漂亮 小鹰眼 去拔箭吧
Good job, hawkeye! go get your arrow.
各位 练得差不多啦 汤出锅咯
Hey, guys. Enough practice. Soup's on.
好的 来啦 我们也饿了
All right. We're coming. We're hungry.
莱拉 走吧
Lila, let's go.
莱拉
Lila?
亲爱的
Honey?
孩子们
Hey, babe?
亲爱的
Babe?
你们人呢
孩子们
Boys!
Boys?
劳拉
Laura?
你别那样
You don't need to do that,
保持这个姿势
Because you're just holding the position.
加油
Come on.
就差一点点
That was close.
进了 打平
That's a goal. We're now one a-piece.
我想再来一次
I would like to try again.
平局了
We're tied up.
感觉到紧张了没 这才是乐趣所在
Feel the tension? It's fun.
糟了 现在你有机会赢我了
That was terrible. Now you have a chance to win.
你赢了 恭喜
And you won. Congratulations.
公平比赛
Fair game.
友好运动
Good sport.
好玩吗
You had fun?
还挺有趣的
It was fun.
启动了没
This thing on?
波兹小姐 佩珀
Hey, miss potts… Pep.
如果你看到了这段录像
If you find this recording…
别发到网上
Don't post it, on social media.
挺伤感的
It's gonna be a rt to talk about.
不知道你能不能看到
I don't know if you're ever gonna see these.
我甚至都不知道你是不是还…
I don't even know if you're still…
希望你还在吧
Oh, god. I hope so…
今天是第21… 22天
Today is day 21… Uh, 22.
要不是这浩瀚宇宙
You know, if it wasn't for the existensial terror of…
让我自觉有些微不足道
Staring into the literal void of space,
我今天过得还挺不错的
I'd say, I'm feeling more better today.
多亏了小蓝妹妹
The infection's run its course,
感染的地方已经好多了
Thanks to the blue…
你肯定会喜欢她 特别干练
You'd love her. Very practical.
就是下手有点重
Only a tiny bit sadistic.
部分燃料仓在作战时炸裂了
Some fuel cells were cracked during battle,
不过我们找到一种方法
But we figured out a way…
利用反向离子充电 争取了48个小时的飞行时间
To reverse the ion charge by ourselves, about, 48 hours of flight time.
不过现在没招了
But it's now dead in the water.
离我们最近的补给站还有1000多光年呢
We're 1, 000 lightyears from the nearest 7-11.
氧气明早就耗尽了
Oxygen will run out tomorrow morning.
到时就结束了
And that'll be it.
佩珀 我
And pep, i…
我曾经说过不会再有意外了
I know I said no more surprises, but…
可我真的希望能完成这最后一次任务
I gotta say, I was really hoping to pull off one last one.
不过现在看来
But it looks like…
想必你也知道了
Well, you know what it looks like.
别为此而难过
Don't feel bad about this.
当然你可以悲痛几周
I mean actually if you grovel for a couple weeks,
然后带着对我的想念继续生活下去吧
And then, move on with enormous guilt…
我得躺下了 放松一下眼睛
I should probably lie down. I'm gonna caress my eyes.
请记住
Please know…
我睡着的时候 就像最近发生的一切一样
When I drift off, it will be like everything lately.
都挺好的 我一切都挺好的
I'm fine… Totally fine.
我会梦到你
I'll dream about you.
梦里一直都是你
Because it's always you.
- 我没能阻止得了他 - 我也没有
- Couldn't stop him. - Neither could I.
我失去那孩子了
I lost the kid.
托尼 我们都失去了
Tony, we lost.
天哪
Oh, my god!
没事了
It's Okay.
灭霸来到地球 已经23天了
It's been 23 days since Thanos came to earth.
各国政府分崩离析
World governments are in pieces.
还在运转的部门
The parts that are still working…
正在做人口统计
Or trying to take a senses…
目前看来他…
And it looks like he did…
他说的话都做到了
He did exactly what he said he was…
灭霸夺去了
Thano wiped out…
一半的生命
Fifty percent of all living creatures.
他现在在哪里
Where is he now? where?
不知道
We don't know.
他就打开了一扇传送门然后走了进去
He just opened a portal and walked through.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他很生气
He's pissed.
他觉得自己失败了
He thinks he failed.
虽然事实如此 不过我们在座的各位
Which of course he did, but you know there's a…
哪位不是失败者呢
Lot of that goin' ad? I need to shav…
说实话 你说话之前
Honestly, at this exact second,
我都以为你是毛绒玩具
I thought you were teddybear..
随你便吧
Maybe I am.
我们追踪灭霸三周了
We've been hunting Thanos for three weeks now.
卫星扫描宇宙都一无所获
Deep space scans, and satellites, and we got nothing.
- 托尼 你跟他交过手 - 谁跟你说的
- Tony you fought him. - Who told you that?
我可不是跟他打架
Didn't fight him.
他直接把一颗星球砸在我脸上
No. He wiped my face with a planet while a…
然后那个玩魔法的就把宝石交给他了
Bleecker street magician gave away the stone.
就是这样 根本就没打
That's what happened. There was no fight…
有没有留下什么线索 坐标什么的
Did he give you any clues? Any coordinates, anything?
我几年前就知道这一切了
I saw this coming a few years back.
我早就料到了 只不过一直不敢相信
I had a vision. I just couldn't believe it…
以为是一场噩梦
Thought I was dreaming.
- 托尼 我需要你专心 - 我曾经也需要过你
- Tony I'm gonna need you to focus. - And I needed you.
但那是过去时了 我当时比你现在更需要
As in, past tense. That trumps what…
一切都晚了 兄弟
You need. It's too late, buddy…
抱歉
Sorry.
知道我现在需要什么吗 我就需要刮个胡子
You know what I need? I need to shave.
- 我记得我以前就说过 - 托尼 托尼 托尼
- And I believe I rememeber telling, - Tony, tony, tony…
无论如何
Why that otherwise,
我们需要的是 用战甲把
That what we needed, was a suit of…
全世界武装起来 还记得吗
Armor around the world, remember that?
不管它是不是侵犯了我们宝贵的自由
Whether it impacted our precious freedoms,
这才是我们需要的
Or not. That's what we needed.
- 那条路也行不通 不是吗 - 我说我们会输的
- Well that didn't work out, did it? - I said we'd lose.
你说 即使输了也一起面对
You said, "we'll do that together, too."
现在好了 队长 我们输了
Well guess what, cap? we lost.
而你当时根本就不在
You weren't there.
不过我们不一直是这样吗 事后诸葛亮
But that's what we do, right? our best work after the fact?
我们是复仇者 只能是复仇者吗 就不能当预防者吗
We're the avengers? We're the avengers? not the prevengers?
好了 我们都听懂了 坐下吧 好吗
Okay. You made your point. Just sit down, Okay?
- 不行 我的意思是… - 她很好
- No, no. Here's my poi… - She's great,
- 顺便夸一下 - 托尼 先坐下
- By the way. - Tony, just sit down…
- 我们需要你 你是新生力量 - 你们这群老倔驴
- We need you. You're new blood. - Bunch of tired old mules…
我什么都给不了你 队长 没有坐标
I got nothing for you, cap. I got no coordinates,
没有线索 没有战术 没有方案
No clues, no strategies, no options…
什么都没有 没有信任可言了 你个骗子
Zero. Zip. Nada. No trust, you liar…
拿着 找到他以后穿上战甲
Here, take this. You find him and you put that on.
然后躲起来
You hide.
- 托尼 - 我没事 我
- Tony! - I'm fine. I…
布鲁斯给了他一针镇静剂
Bruce gave him a sedative. He's gonna…
他今天可能就醒不过来了
Probably be out for the rest of the day.
你们照顾好他 我回来时
You guys take care of him. and I'll bring…
给他带一瓶佐立安灵药
An bezurian elixir when I come back…
- 你要去哪 - 杀灭霸
- Where are you going? - To kill thanos.
我们一般都是团队作战
You know we usually work as a team here, and…
而且我们现在还有点摩擦
Between you and I we're also a little fragile.
我们知道太空可能是你的领域
We realize up there is more your…
不过这也是我们的战争
Territory but this's our fight too.
- 你知道他在哪吗 - 我知道谁也许会知道
- You even know where he is? - I know people who might.
不必折腾了
Don't bother.
我可以告诉你们灭霸在哪里
I can tell you where thanos is.
灭霸用了很长时间让我变得完美
Thanos spent a long time trying to perfect me.
他教导我时 说了他的宏伟计划
And when he worked, he talked about his great plan.
当时即使我被大卸八块 也想让他开心
Even disassembled, I wanted to please him.
我会问他 当我们大功告成时 我们将何去何从
I'd ask, where would we go once his plan was complete?
他的答案永远都是
His answer was always the same.
去那个花园
To the garden.
真有意思 灭霸居然也想要采菊东篱下
That's cute. Thanos has a retirement plan.
所以他到底在哪
So where is he?
灭霸打了响指以后
When thanos snapped his fingers,
地球变成了一个毁灭性能量
Earth became ground zero for a power surge…
爆发的爆心投影点
Of ridiculously coson of a bitch.
从来没人见过那么大的能量 直到两天以前
No one's ever seen anything like it… Until two days ago.
在这颗星球上
On this planet.
灭霸在那里
Thanos is there.
他又一次使用了宝石
He used the stones again.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey…
我们现在人手不够
We'd be going in short-handed, you know?
- 而且宝石还在他手上 - 那我们就抢回来
- Look, he still got the stones, so… - So let's get'em.
- 然后用宝石让所有人复活 - 就这么简单吗
- We use them to bring everyone back. - Just like that?
对 就这么简单
Yeah. Just like that.
即使成功的机率再小 我们也不得不放手一搏
Even if there's a small chance that we can undo this…
为了逝去的战友 一切都是值得的
I mean, we owe it to everyone who's not in this room to try.
如果我们这样做的话
If we do this, how do we know it's gonna…
我们怎么知道结果会和上次不一样
End any differently as it did before.
因为上次 你们没有我
Because before, you didn't have me.
嘿 姑娘 现在这间屋子里的所有人
Hey, new girl, everybody in this…
都是超级英雄
Room is about that super hero life.
我冒昧地问一句
And if you don't mind my asking,
之前那么长时间你都去哪了
Where the hell have you been all this time?
在宇宙中还有许多星球
There are a lot of other planets in the universe.
这些星球上甚至没有像你们一样的超级英雄
And unfortunately, they didn't have you guys.
我喜欢这个新朋友
I like this one.
我们去干掉这个混蛋
Let's go get this son of a bitch.
《复仇者联盟4：终局之战》
- 好了 有谁没上过太空 - 怎么了
- Okay. Who here hasn't been to space? - Why?
你们最好不要吐在我的飞船上
You better not throw up on my ship.
准备跃迁 三 二 一
Approaching jump in 3.. 2.. 1.
我先去侦查一下
I'll head down for recon.
- 我们一定会成功的 史蒂夫 - 我知道
- This is gonna work, steve. - I know it will.
因为除了成功 我别无选择
Because I don't know what I'm gonna do if it doesn't.
没有卫星 没有飞船 没有军队
No satellites, no ships, no armies,
也没有地面防御
No ground defenses…
只有他自己
It's just him.
这就足够了
Then that's enough.
噢 不
Oh, no.
宝石在哪里
Where are they?
回答他
Answer the question.
宇宙需要被改善
The universe required correction.
在此之后 宝石除了诱惑 已别无他用
After that, the stones served no purpose, beyond temptation.
你杀害了数万亿生命
You murdered trillions!
你们应该感激我
You should be grateful.
- 宝石在哪里 - 消失了
- Where are the stones? - Gone.
- 化为了灰烬 - 你两天前还用过
- Reduced to atoms. - You used them two days ago.
我用宝石的力量毁掉了宝石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
差点让我送了性命
It nearly killed me.
但是任务还是圆满完成了 注定如此
But the work is done. It always will be.
我 就是公理
I am inevitable.
我们把这个地方翻个底朝天 他一定在说谎
We have to tear this place apart. He has to be lying.
我父亲什么事都可能做
My father is many things.
唯独不会说谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你 宝贝女儿
Thank you, daughter.
是我以前对你太严厉了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly…
什么 你干了什么
What… What did you do?
这次我是冲着他的脑袋去的
I went for the head.
（五年后）
所以我
So i, uh…
（他们不在了 我们何去何从）
找了个时间 约人吃了顿饭
Went on a date the other day.
五年来这还是头一遭
It's the first time in five years,
你知道吗 坐在餐桌旁
You know? sit down to dinner…
竟然不知道该说些什么
I didn't know what to talk about.
你们聊了什么
What did you talk about?
都是老套的梗 怎么时过境迁的 还有
Same old crap, you know? how things have changed, and…
我的工作 他的工作
My job, his job….
还有我们有多怀念纽约大都会球队
How much we miss the mets.
然后我们都无话可说了
Then things get quiet..
在上沙拉的时候 他哭了
He cried as they were serving the salads.
那你呢
What about you?
快上甜点的时候 我也哭了
I cried just before dessert.
但是明天我和他还会见面 所以
But I'm seeing him again tomorrow, so…
非常好
That's great.
你已经度过了最艰难的时刻 你迈出了关键的第一步
You did the hardest part. You took the jump, you…
虽然不知道接下来会面对什么
Didn't know where you were gonna come down.
是啊 虽然是很小的一步
And that's it. That's those little,
千里之行 始于足下
Brave baby stepse that he left..
让我们重新团结起来 找到目标
To try and become whole again. To try and find purpose.
1945年 我被封在冰里
I went in the ice in '45 right…
在那之前 我刚遇到我的一生挚爱
After I met the love of my life.
醒来已是70年以后
Woke up 70 years later.
但我不得不面对现实
You got to move on.
继续前进
Got to move on.
这个世界的命运掌握在我们手中
The world is in our hands.
这是我们的职责
It's left to us guys.
我们不得不肩负起使命
And we got to do something with it.
否则
Otherwise…
灭霸本来可以把我们都杀掉的
Thanos should've killed all of us.
（旧金山）
（私人仓库）
怎么回事
What the hell?
霍普
Hope?
（救命）
（寻人启事）
孩子 嘿 孩子
Kid! hey, kid!
这里发生了什么
What the hell happened here?
（逝者）
我的天呐
My god…
不要 拜托 拜托 不 不 不
No. Please. Please, please. No, no, no…
请让一下 不好意思 不 凯茜 不
Excuse me. Sorry. No, cassie, no.
不要
No.
不 不
No, no.
不要 不要 不要
Please, please, please, please….
不要有凯茜
No, cassie…
（斯科特·朗）
什么
What?
凯茜
Cassie?
爸爸
Dad?
你都长这么大了
You're so big!
（禁止入内）
好了 我们登上了丹佛斯发现的那艘可疑的飞船
Yeah, we boarded that highly suspect warship danvers pinged.
应该说是破烂不堪的垃圾船
It was an infectious garbage scale.
哦 谢谢你这个情报
So, thanks for the hot tip.
- 当时你们离飞船更近吧 - 没错
- Well, you were closer. - Yeah.
现在我们身上还有一股垃圾味儿
And now we smell like garbage.
你们注意到那些震颤声了吗
You get a reading on those tremors?
就是非洲板块的地壳运动而已
It was a mild subduction under the african plate.
有影像吗 怎么处理的
Do we have a visual? how are we handling it?
娜塔莎 只是海底地震而已
Nat, it's an earthquake under the ocean.
不处理就是最正确的处理方式
We handle it by not handling it.
卡罗尔 下个月你还在吗
Carol, are we seeing you here next month?
- 恐怕不在 - 为什么 又要换新发型吗
- Not likely. - What, you gonna get another haircut?
听好了 毛脸儿 还有很多事等着我去做
Listen, fur-face. I'm covering a lot of territory.
和地球一样处于险境的星球
The things that are happening on earth are…
比比皆是 成百上亿
Happening everywhere, on thousands of planets.
这个解释不错 你说的都对
That's a good point. That's a good point.
所以你们可能会有很长一段时间见不到我
So you might not see me for a long time.
好吧 呃
All right. Uh, well…
这个频道会一直开着 所以如果出了什么意外的话
This channel is always active. So, anything goes sideways…
或者有人找麻烦的话
Anyone's making trouble where they shouldn't…
- 记得找我 - 没问题
- Comes through me. - Okay.
好的
All right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
- 你在哪儿 - 墨西哥
- Where are you? - Mexico.
联邦部队发现了一个屋子 里面全是尸体
The federales found a room full of bodies.
看起来像一群黑帮
Looks like a bunch of cartel guys. Never…
还没来得及开枪还手
Even had the chance to take their guns…
- 说不定是黑吃黑 - 绝对不是
- It's probably a rival gang… - Except it isn't.
这绝对是巴顿干的
It's definitely barton.
他的所作所为 还有他
What he's done here, what he's…
过去几年的行径
Been doing for the last few years.
还有他造成的那些影响
I mean, the scene that he left…
说实话 有些时候我真的
I gotta tell you, there's a part of…
一点也不想去找他
Me that doesn't even want to find him…
你能查出他接下来会去哪里吗
Will you find out where he's going next?
娜塔莎
Nat…
求你了
Please.
好吧
Yeah.
我本来想给你做顿晚饭的
You know I'd offer to cook you dinner…
但是看来你情绪非常糟糕
But you seem pretty miserable already.
你是来洗衣服的
You here to do your laundry?
顺便来看看你
And to see a friend.
很明显 我很好
Clearly, your friend is fine.
我今天过桥的时候
You know I saw a pod of whales…
看到了一群鲸鱼
When I came across a bridge?
- 是哈德逊河吗 - 船很少 水很清澈
- In the hudson? - There's fewer ships, cleaner water.
如果你要鼓励我
You know, if you're about to tell…
积极乐观地面对生活
Me to look on the bright side.
呃
Um…
我会把三明治
I'm about to hit you in the head…
砸你脸上
With a peanut sandwich…
不好意思 我老毛病又犯了
Sorry. Force of habit.
我一直在告诉所有人
You know I keep telling everybody…
要学会放下过去 学会成长
They should move on, grow?
有的人可以
Some do.
但我们不行
But not us.
如果我放过自己 谁来替我做这些
If I move on, who does this?
也许根本没必要做这些
Maybe it doesn't need being done.
我曾经一无所有
I used to have nothing.
但如今我拥有了现在的一切
And then I got this.
这份工作
This job.
这个大家庭
This family.
让我变得更好
And I was… I was better because of it.
即使现在
And even though…
他们都不在了
They're gone…
我还是想让自己变得更好
Now, I'm still trying to be better.
我想我们俩都应该重新开始了
I think we both need to get a life.
你先来
You first.
你好 你好
Oh… Hi. Hi!
有人在吗 我是斯科特·朗
Is anyone home? this is scott lang.
我们几年前见过 在德国的机场
We met a few years ago, at the airport? in germany?
我变得非常非常大 还戴了个面具
I got really big and I had my mask on.
- 你们可能认不出我来 - 这是以前的录像吗
- You wouldn't recognize me. - Is this an old message?
蚁人记得吗 蚁人 我知道你们认识
Ant-man? ant-man, I know you know that.
这个大门口的监控
It's the front gate.
我需要跟你们谈谈
I need to talk to you guys.
斯科特
Scott.
- 你还好吗 - 挺好
- Are you Okay? - Yeah.
你们有谁学过量子物理吗
Have either of you guys ever studied quantum physics?
只听说过
Only in mid-conversation.
好吧 那
Alright. So…
五年前 就在灭霸那事之前
Five years ago, right before… Thanos,
那时我在一个叫量子领域的地方
I was in a place called the quantum realm.
量子领域就像是一个独立的微观宇宙
The quantum realm is like its own microscopic universe.
想要进去 就得变得
To get in there, you have to be…
非常非常小 霍普是
Incredibly small. Hope…
她是 她曾经是我的
She… She was my…
她本应该把我从量子领域拉出来的
She was supposed to pull me out.
但是灭霸出现了
And then Thanos happened.
- 我就被困住了 - 抱歉
- I got stuck in there. - Sorry.
这五年你一定很漫长
That must've been very long five years.
这就是我想说的 并不漫长
Yeah, but that's just it. It wasn't.
对我来说 只是五个小时而已
For me it was five hours.
明白了吗 量子领域的规则
See, the rules of the quantum realm…
和宏观世界的不一样
Aren't like they are appeared.
一切都无法预测 那是
Everything is unpredictable. Is that…
谁的三明治啊 我快饿死了
Anybody's sandwich? I am starving.
斯科特
Scott.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
就是
So…
我想说的是
What I'm saying is…
量子领域的时间运行和现实世界不一样
Time works differently in the quantum realm.
现在唯一的问题是
The only problem is right now,
我们还不知道怎么操控它
We don't have a way to navigate it.
但如果我们找到方法呢
But what if we did?
我止不住地想 如果
I can't stop thinking about it. What…
我们能操控这种无序性
If we could somehow control the chaos…
使它为我们所用呢 如果
And we could navigate it? what if…
我们能在一个特定的时间
There was a way to enter…
进入量子领域 然后
The quantum realm at a certain point in time but then…
再从另外一个时间点离开量子领域呢 比如
Exit the quantum realm at another point in time? like…
比如灭霸到来之前
Like before Thanos.
等等 你在说时间机器吗
Wait, are you talking about a time machine?
不 不 当然不是 不是时间机器
No. No, of course not. No, not a time machine.
更像是
It's more like a…
好吧 就是时间机器 我知道这很疯狂 很疯狂
Yeah, like a time machine. I know. It's crazy. It's crazy.
但我一直在想 肯定有…
But I can't stop thinking about it. There's gotta be…
- 某种方法…是太疯狂了 - 斯科特
- Some wa… It's crazy. - Scott.
我还能收到浣熊发来的邮件呢 所以
I get e-mails from a raccoon. So,
没什么事称得上是疯狂了
Nothing sounds crazy anymore.
我们要和谁商量这事
So who do we talk to about this?
吃饭饭啦
Chow-time!
小摩根
Morgoona.
摩根·史塔克 想不想吃午饭
Morgan h. Stark. Want some lunch?
- 说 午饭吃什么 不然我就消灭你 - 好好好
- Define lunch or be disintegrated. - Okay.
你不应该穿这个的 知道吗
You should not be wearing that, Okay?
这是我给妈妈准备的
That is part of a special anniversary…
周年礼物
Gift made for mom.
脱下来吧 你午饭想吃什么
There you go. are you thinking about lunch?
生菜卷蟋蟀可以吗
Want a handful of crickets in a bit of lettuce?
- 不要 - 你不想试试吗
- No. - That's what you want.
- 你怎么找到这个的 - 在车库里啊
- How did you find this? - Garage.
真的吗
Really?
- 你特意去找的吗 - 不是啊
- Were you looking for it? - No.
就是无意中找到的
I found it, though.
你喜欢去车库玩吗 爸爸也是
You like going to the garage, huh? so does daddy.
不过没关系 反正妈妈也不会戴
It's fine actually. Mom never wears anything I buy her.
我们知道这听起来
Now, we know what it sounds like…
托尼 经历了这么多之后
Tony, after everything you've seen,
还有什么是不可能的吗
Is anything really…
量子波动会扰乱普朗克尺度
Quantum fluctuation messes with the planck scale,
继而引发德意志命题
Which then triggers the Deutsch Proposition.
是这个意思吗
Can we agree with him?
谢谢
Thank you.
简单的说就是 你们回不来的
In layman's terms, it means you're not coming home.
- 我回来了啊 - 不
- I did. - No.
你是碰巧活下来了 这
You accidentally survived. It's a…
这是十亿分之一的概率
It's a billion-to-one cosmic fluke.
现在你还想
And now you wanna pull a…
你刚才怎么说来着
What do you call it?
- 时空抢劫 - 对 时空抢劫
- A time heist? - Yeah. Time heist.
对哦 我们之前怎么没想到这个方法呢
Of course. Why didn't we think of this before?
我想起来了 因为这个方法太可笑了 就是白日做梦
Oh! because it's laughable? because it's a pipedream?
过去有宝石 我们
The stones are in the past. We…
可以回到过去 拿到宝石
Can go back and…
然后我们自己打响指 把大家都带回来
We can snap our own fingers. We can bring everybody back.
或者把现实弄得更糟糕 对吗
Or screw it up worse than he already has, right?
我们不会搞砸的
I don't believe we would.
不得不说 我还挺怀念这种盲目乐观的
Gotta say this. Sometimes, I miss that giddy optimism.
可是 如果我们没有一个安全可行的方法
However, high hopes won't help if there's no logical,
来进行这个所谓的时空抢劫 期望再高也没有用
Tangible, way for me to safely execute said time heist.
我觉得最可能的结果
I believe the most likely outcome…
是我们全军覆没
Will be our colecond chance.
如果我们严格遵循时间旅行的规则 肯定不会有事的
Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.
不跟过去的自己说话
That means no talking to our past selves,
不买体育彩票
No betting on sports events.
我打断一下 斯科特
I'm gonna stop you right there, scott.
你是要告诉我 你拯救宇宙的计划
Are you seriously telling me that your plan to…
是看《回到未来》想出来的吗
Save the universe is based on back to the future?
- 不是啊 - 那就好 吓我一跳
- No. - Good. You had me worried there.
那部电影是瞎编的
'cause that'd be horseshit.
量子物理不是这么用的
That's not how quantum physics works?
托尼
Tony…
我们得坚定立场
We have to take a stand.
我们坚定过啊 但结果就是这样
We did stand. and yet, here we are.
我知道你现在有很多顾虑
I know you got a lot on the line.
你有妻有女
You got a wife, a daughter.
但是我失去了对我很重要的人
But I lost someone very important…
还有很多人和我一样
To me. a lot of people did…
而现在 现在我们有机会
And now, now, we have a chance to bring…
把她 把所有人带回来
Her back, to bring everyone back…
你却告诉我你连试都不愿意试吗
And you're telling me that you won't even…
对 斯科特 我不愿意
That's right, scott. I won't.
我做不到
I can't.
妈妈叫我来救你了
Mommy told me to come and save you.
太好了 我得救了
Good job. I'm saved.
我很希望你们今天不是为了这件事来找我
I wish you'd come here to ask me something else.
其他什么都可以 说真的 见到你们很高兴
Anything else. Honestly, happy to see you guys, it was…
- 留下来吃个饭吧 - 托尼 我明白
- Oh, and table's set for six. - Tony, I get it.
我很替你高兴 真的
And I'm happy for you. I really am.
但这是我们的第二次机会
But this is a second chance.
这里就是我的第二次机会 队长
I got my second chance right here, cap.
我不能再冒险了
I can't roll the dice again.
留下来吃午饭吧 别聊这个话题就行
If you don't talk shop, you can stay for lunch.
- 他害怕了 - 他也没错
- He's scared. - He's not wrong.
但我们该怎么办呢
Yeah, but I mean, what are we gonna do?
我们需要他 就这样放弃吗
We need him. What, are we gonna stop?
不 但是要谨慎行事
No. I wanna do it right.
我们需要一个聪明的帮手
We're gonna need a really big brain.
比他还聪明吗
Bigger than his?
你们都吃点吧 怎么
Come on. I feel like I'm the only…
只有我一个人在吃
One eating here.
来点鸡蛋
Have some eggs.
我不太能理解
I'm so confused.
- 不能理解的事情多着呢 - 对 不 不是
- These are confusing times. - Right. No, no…
- 我不是这个意思 - 我懂
- That's not what I meant. I… - No, I get it.
跟你开玩笑呢 我知道 这很疯狂
I'm kidding! I know. It's crazy.
- 我都开始穿衬衣了 - 对啊 怎么做到的 为什么会这样
- I'm wearing shirts now. - Yeah! How? why?
五年前我们输了
Five years ago we got our asses beat.
但是对我来说更糟糕 因为我相当于输了两次
Except it was worse for me. Because I lost twice.
先是浩克输了 然后班纳输了 最后我们都输了
First, hulk lost. Then banner lost. Then, we all lost.
- 没人怪你 布鲁斯 - 但我自责
- No one blamed you, bruce. - I did.
这么多年来 我都把浩克当做
For years I've been treating the hulk like he's…
一种病来治 想尽办法摆脱他
Some kind of disease, something to get rid of.
但是后来我把他看作一种解药
But then I started looking at him as the cure.
我在伽马射线实验室呆了18个月
Eighteen months in a gamma lab. I put…
将智慧和力量融合在一起
The brains and bron together…
看看现在 两者完美结合在一起了
And now look at me. Best of both worlds.
- 不好意思 浩克先生 - 怎么了
- Excuse me, mr. Hulk? - Yes?
- 能和您合个影吗 - 当然可以了 小朋友
- Can we get a photo? - 100%, little person.
来吧 靠近点 能给我们拍吗
Come on, step on up. You mind?
- 行啊 - 谢谢
- Oh. Yeah. - Thanks.
说 茄子
Say "green."
茄子
Greeeen.
- 拍好了吗 - 拍好了
- Did you get that? - That's good.
你们不想和我拍吗 我是蚁人
Don't you wanna grab one with me? I'm ant-man.
他们是绿巨人粉丝，根本都不认识蚁人
They're hulk fans. They don't know ant-man.
- 没人认识我 - 等下 不会的 他想的
- Nobody does. - Wait, no, no, he wants to…
你们也想和他合影对不对呀
You want to take a picture with him, right?
他都说他不想拍了 我理解的
He's even saying no he doesn't. I get it.
我也不想拍 我也不想跟他们合影
I don't want it either. I don't want a picture with them.
- 他会很伤心的 - 抱歉
- He's gonna feel bad. - Sorry.
- 孩子们说他们想拍 - 我不想拍了
- They said they'd do it. - I don't want it anymore.
- 你会不开心的 - 把手机拿走
- You'd feel bad… - Take the goddamn phone.
谢谢你 浩克先生
Thank you, mr. Hulk.
没事孩子们 也谢谢你们
No, it's great, kids. Thank you very much.
- 浩克出击 - 布鲁斯
- Hulk out! - Bruce.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
听妈妈的话 她什么都知道
Listen to your mom. She knows better.
- 我们回到正题 - 好的
- About we were saying… - Right.
把时间旅行那套再说一遍吗
The whole time travel do-over?
伙计们 这就触及到我的知识盲区了
Guys, it's outside of my area of expertise.
你都已经把自己变成这样了
Well, you pulled this off.
我记得以前这也是不太可能的吧
I remember a time when that seemed pretty impossible, too.
让我看看这个灵感能不能行得通吧
Look at a mod inspiration, let me see what checks out.
那么 在今晚睡觉之前
So, recommend one last sim before…
我们再做一次模拟
We pack it in tt. You got th…
这次在莫比乌斯环里翻转过来 好吗
This time, in the shape of a mobius strip, inverted. Please?
处理中
Processing…
把特征值告诉我 那个
Give me that eigenvalue. That,
还有粒子分解和光谱分析
Particle factoring and spectral decon…
- 看来要费点功夫 - 请稍等
- That'll take a second. - Just a moment.
没结果也无所谓 我只是想。.
And don't worry if it doesn't pan out. I'm just kinda…
模型渲染完毕
Model rendered.
该死
Shit!
你怎么还没睡呀 小姑娘
What are you doing up, little miss?
- 该死 - 不行 我们不可以这么说
- Shit. - No. We don't say that.
只有妈妈可以说这个词 她发明的 这是她的专属词
Only mommy says that word. She coined it, it belongs to her.
怎么还不睡
Why you up?
因为我这还有些该死的
'cause I got some important shit…
重要的工作要做 不然呢
Going on here. What do you think…
不是 我在想事情 我有些事没想明白
No, I got something on my mind. I got something on my mind.
- 你在想果汁冰棍吗 - 对啊
- Was it juice pops? - Sure was.
你给我下套呢，你想要哪样的
That's extortion. What kind you want?
英雄所见略同 果汁冰棍 我想的
Great minds think alike. Juice pops, exactly was on…
就是这个
My mind.
你吃完了吗 现在没有了
You done? Yeah? Now you are.
- 小脸蛋 躺下吧 - 给我讲个故事
- That face, goes there. - Tell me a story.
故事
A story.
很久很久以前 小摩根上床睡觉了 完了
Once upon a time, mongoona went to bed. The end.
这故事太没意思了
That is a horrible story.
哎呀 这可是你最爱的故事呀
Come on, that's your favorite story.
爱你一千遍
I love you tons.
那我爱你三千遍
I love you 3, 000.
哇哦
Wow.
三千遍 太疯狂啦
3, 000. That's crazy.
睡觉吧 要不我就把你的玩具都卖掉
Go to bed. Or I'll sell all your toys.
安安
Night-night.
不是炫耀什么 但是她说她爱我三千遍
Not that it's a competition, but she loves me 3, 000.
现在也是吗
Does she now?
你也就六百到九百遍左右吧
You were somewhere in the low 6 to 900 range.
- 你在看什么 - 只是本有关有机肥的书
- What you reading? - Just a book on composting.
有机肥有什么新闻吗
What's new with composting?
- 就… - 我搞定了
- Just …. - I figured it out…
顺便一说
By the way.
我们说的是同一个话题吗
You know, just so we're talking about the same thing…
时间旅行
Time travel.
什么
What?
哇哦
Wow.
这真是
That's…
神奇 而且可怕。.
Amazing, and…. Terrifying.
是啊
That's right.
- 我们很幸运了 - 嗯 我知道
- I got really lucky. - Yeah. I know.
- 很多人都没有这么幸运 - 不 我不可能帮助所有人
- A lot of people didn't. - No, I can't help everybody.
- 你明明可以 - 我不再继续研究就不能了
- It sorta seems like you can. - Not if I stop.
我可以直接收手 停下不干
I can put a pin in it right now, and stop.
托尼
Tony…
想让你收手
Trying to get you to stop has been one…
估计我这一辈子应该是做不到了
Of the few failure of my entire life…
我有时候觉得我不应该提这事的
I sometimes feel I should put it in a locked…
应该把它直接忘得一干二净
Box and drop it at thhh… The van thing.
然后上床休息
Go to bed.
但是你能睡得安稳吗
But would you be able to rest?
好了 开始吧 时空穿梭第一次试验
Okay, here we go. Time travel test number one.
斯科特，启动那个 呃 卡车里的东西
Scott, fire up the, uhh… The van thing.
断路器设置完毕 应急发电机已就绪
Breakers are set. Emergency generators are on standby.
很好 如果突然断电了
Good. 'cause if we blow the grid, I don't…
我可不想把这个小不点落在上世纪五十年代
Wanna lose tiny he…
- 你说什么 - 他开玩笑呢
- Excuse me? - He's kidding.
你别吓唬他
You can't say things like that.
就是个不怎么样的玩笑
Just… It was, just a bad joke.
- 你是开玩笑吧 - 我也不知道
- You were kidding, right? - I have no idea.
我们现在说的可是时空穿梭
We're talking about time travel here.
要不就是彻彻底底的玩笑 要不就全完蛋
Either it's all a jokectly not confusing.
没问题了 把你的头盔戴上
We're good! get your helmet on.
斯考特 我要把你送回一周之前 但是你
Scott, I'm gonna send you back a week, but you'll walk…
只会停留差不多一个小时的时间 然后我们在10秒内把你带回来
Around for an hour, then bring you back in 10 seconds.
- 懂了吗 - 清楚明白
- Makes sense? - Perfectly not confusing.
祝你好运 斯科特 你做得到的
Good luck, scott. You got this.
没错 我做得到 美国队长
You're right. I do, captain america.
倒计时开始 三 二 一
On the count of three. 3.. 2.. 1..
各位 好像不太对劲
Guys? this doesn't feel right.
- 怎么回事 等下 - 那是谁
- What's going on? hold on. - Who is that?
- 那是斯科特吗 - 是 我就是斯科特
- Is that scott? - Yes, it's scott!
哦 我的后背
Ooh! my back!
给我让个位置
Can I get a little space?
- 你能把他带回来吗 - 我在弄呢
- Can you bring him back? - I'm working on it!
这是个婴儿
It's a baby.
- 是斯科特 - 婴儿时期的斯科特
- It's scott. - As a baby!
- 他会长大的嘛 - 把斯科特带回来
- He'll grow. - Bring scott back.
我说切断电源的时候就切断它
When I say kill the power, kill the power.
我的天哪
Oh, my god…
好 断电
And… Kill it!
有人把我裤子尿湿了
Somebody peed my pants.
哦 谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
但是我也不知道是婴儿的我还是老年的我尿的
But, I don't know if it was "baby" me or "old" me.
也或许 就是我自己尿的
Or, just "me" me.
时空穿梭
Time travel!
怎么了
What?
我觉得这可是大功告成啊
I see this as an absolute win.
拉着个脸干嘛
Why the long face?
我猜猜看 他变成了个婴儿
Let me guess. He turned into a baby.
还变成其他的了呢 是 你来这做什么
Among other things, yeah. What are you doing here?
这就是艾波罗悖论
That's the epr paradox.
不是朗在时间中穿梭
Instead of pushing lang through time, you…
而是时间在朗体内穿梭
Might've wound up pushegardless, I fixed it.
很复杂 也很危险
It's tricky. Dangerous.
应该有人警告你们的
Somebody coulda cautiormir are laid in.
- 你警告过 - 哦 是吗
- You did. - Oh, did i?
谢天谢地我来了 不管怎样 我修复了它
Thank god, I'm here. Regardless, I fixed it.
一个功能齐全的时空穿梭导航器
A fully functioning time-space gps.
我只想要讲和
I just want peace.
仇恨太耗费精力了 我不喜欢这样
Turns out, resentment is corrosive, and I hate it.
我也是
Me, too.
我们可以再冒一次险
We got a shot at getting these stones, but i…
但是我要先告诉你对我来说什么最重要
Gotta tell you my priority is to bring back…
把我们失去的拿回来 我当然也希望
What we lost? I hope, yes.
但我会不计任何代价保护我现有的一切
Keep what I found? I have to, at all costs.
然后 如果能不那么寻死当然就更好了
And, maybe not die trying will be nice.
那就说定了
Sounds like a deal.
- 托尼 我不确定 - 为什么 他为你而造的
- Tony, I don't know… - Why? he made it for you.
另外呢 我也得把它从车库拿出来
Plus, honestly I have to get it out the…
不然摩根就拿去当滑板了
Garage before morgang story, though.
谢谢你 托尼
Thank you, tony.
你能低调点吗
Will you keep that a little quiet?
我可没给每个人都准备小礼物
Didn't bring one fah, noobmaster69.
人都齐了 对吧
We are getting, the whole team, yeah?
我们正在召集他们回来
We're working on that right now.
- 嘿 兄弟 绿大个二在哪呢 - 厨房吧可能
- Hey, humie! where's the green? - Kitchen. I think.
- 不错啊这身 - 罗德 回来的时候小心点
- That's awesome. - Rhodey, careful on re-entry.
着陆区有个傻子
There's an idiot in the landing zone.
哦 天啊
Oh, god!
怎么变正常大小了
What's up, regular-sized man?
（欢迎来到新阿斯加德 请减速慢行）
这个跟什么金色宫殿啊
Kind of a step down from a golden palace…
魔法锤子啊差了几个档次啊好像
With some magic hammers and what that…
有点同情心吧兄弟
Hey, have a little compassion,
他们失去了阿斯加德
Pal. First, they lost Asgard…
然后又失去了一半的人口
Then half the people. They're…
他们有个地方落脚已经很满足了
Probably just happy to have a home…
你们不该来的
You shouldn't have come!
女武神
Valkyrie!
很高兴见到你 凶丫头
Great to see you, angry girl.
我觉得你原来哪种模样都比现在这样都强
I think I liked you better either of the other ways.
- 这是火箭 - 你好啊
- This is rocket. - How you doin'?
- 他不会见你们的 - 这么糟糕吗
- He won't see you. - That bad, huh?
我们只一个月见一次面 在他来
We only see him once a month, when he comes in for…
拿补给的时候
supplies.
- 这种糟糕啊 - 对啊
- It's that bad. - Yeah.
天哪
What the…
有东西死在这了吗
Woo! something died in here.
有人吗 索尔
Hello? thor?
你们是修有线电视的吗
Are you here about the cable?
电影频道两周前就不能看了
The cinemax ran out two weeks ago,
体育频道也不太清楚
And, sports were all kind of fuzzy…
索尔
Thor?
兄弟们 哦 天哪
Boys! oh, my god!
天哪 见到你们真高兴
My god! It's so good to see you!
快过来 你这个小淘气包
Come here, you little rascal!
不 我这样就挺好 我挺好
No, I'm good! I'm good.
不用这么热情
That's not necessary!
浩克 你认识我朋友米克和克罗格 对吧
Hulk, you know my friends, miek, korg, right?
- 嘿 兄弟们 - 嘿 好久不见
- Hey, boys! - Hey, guys. Long time no see.
啤酒在桶里 无线随便用
Beer's on the bucket. Feel free to log on to the wi-fi.
直接连 没有密码
No password, obviously.
索尔 他又来了 电视里那个小子
Thor, he's back. That kid on the tv…
刚才又说我蠢了
Just called me a dicky again…
- 菜鸟王 - 是的 菜鸟王69
- Noobmaster - Yeah, noobmaster69.
这回看我的
Let's see this…
菜鸟王 又是我 索尔
Noobmaster. Hey, it's thor again.
你知道的 我是雷神
You know, the God of Thunder.
听着 小朋友 如果你不立刻下线
Listen, buddy. If you don't log off…
我就会飞到你家去
This game immediately, I'm gonna fly…
找到你
Over to your house, come down to…
藏身的地下室
That basement you are hiding in…
扯掉你的胳膊 然后塞到你屁屁里去
Rip off your arms then shove them up your butt!
哦 就是这样
Oh, that's right. Yes, go cry to…
去找爸爸哭吧 你个胆小鬼
Your father, you little weasel…
谢谢 索尔
Thank you, thor.
他再烦你 你就告诉我
Let me know if he bothers you again, Okay?
非常感谢 我会的
Thank you very much. I will.
所以你们要喝点什么吗 你们喝什么
So you guys want a drink? what are you drinking?
我们有啤酒 龙舌兰 一应俱全
We've got beer, tequila, all sorts of things.
兄弟 你还好吗
Buddy, you all right?
好啊 我很好 为什么这么问 我看起来不好吗
Yes, I'm fine! why, don't you think I look all right?
你看上去就像一滩化掉的冰淇淋
You look like melted ice cream.
所以你们是来干什么的
So, what's up or what…
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help. There might be…
或许有一个可以让一切恢复正常的机会
A chance we could fix everything…
什么 比如修好那台电视吗
What, like the cable 'cause that's…
因为那玩意儿几周前就已经把我逼疯了
Been driving me through weeks…
比如灭霸
Like thanos.
不许提这个名字
Don't say that name.
没错 在这里我们都不提这个名字的
Um, yeah. We don't actually say that name in here.
请你松手
Please take your hand off me.
我知道
Now, I know that…
那个家伙或许让你感到恐惧
Guy might scare you.
为什么 为什么我会
Why would I be? why would,
为什么我会害怕他
Why would I be scary about that guy?
是我亲手杀了那个家伙 记得吗
I'm the one who killed that guy, remember?
还有谁可以杀得了他吗
Anyone else here killed that guy?
不 我觉得没有
Nope. Didn't think so.
克罗格 为什么你不提醒大家
Korg, why don't you, tell everybody…
是谁砍下了灭霸的大脑袋
Who chopped thanos' big head off…
额 暴风战斧吗
Umm… Stormbreaker?
那是谁在使用暴风战斧
Now, who's swinging stormbreaker?
我懂的 你现在很纠结
I get it. You're in a rough spot,
我曾经也有过这样的时候
Okay? I've been there myself…
你知道是谁帮助我走出来了吗
You wanna know who helped me out of it?
我不知道 是 娜塔莎吗
I don't know. Is it… Natasha?
是你
It was you.
你帮助了我
You helped me.
为什么你不去问问那些阿斯加德人
Why don't you ask the, asgardians down there,
我的帮助对他们来说有没有意义
How much my help was worth.
反正他们已经离开了
The ones that are left, anyway.
我们也许可以把他们带回来
I think we can bring them back.
住口 别说了
Stop. Just, stop…
我知道你觉得我在这里自怨自艾
I know you think I'm down here wallowing in…
等待着被救赎
My own self-pity, waiting to be rescued…
但是我没事好吗 我们挺好的 对吧
And saved. But I'm fine, Okay? we're fine, aren't we?
没错 我们很好 朋友
Nah, all good here, mate!
所以不管你们怎么说 我们都不想去
So, whatever it is that you're offering, we're…
不关心 完全不关心
Not into it, don't care, couldn't care less.
再见
Goodbye.
我们需要你 老兄
We need you, pal.
飞船上有啤酒
There's beer on the ship.
哪种啤酒
What kind?
（东京）
就是他
他在追明彦
你为什么要这么做
我们和你无冤无仇
你们活下来了
半个星球的人都没有
他们遇到的是灭霸
你遇到的不过是我
休想再滥杀无辜了
我们滥杀无辜
你疯了
去死吧
等等 救救我
让我做什么都可以
你想要什么
我想要的
What I want.
你给不起
You can't give me.
你不该来这里
You shouldn't be here.
你也不该
Neither should you.
我有工作要做
I've got a job to do.
你管这个叫工作吗
Is that what you're calling this?
杀再多人你的家人也回不来了
Killing all these people isn't gonna bring your family back.
我们找到了办法
We found something.
或许是个机会
A chance, maybe…
不要
Don't.
不要什么
Don't what?
不要给我希望
Don't give me hope.
很抱歉我没能早些给你希望
I'm sorry I couldn't give it to you sooner.
让开 让开点 勒保斯基
Drifting left. On the side there, lebowski.
- 小贱箭 怎么样了 - 我叫火箭
- Ratchet, how's it going? - It's rocket.
淡定点 你也就能在地球上算是个天才
Take it easy. You're only a genius on earth, pal.
没错
Yup.
时间穿梭服 不错呀
Time travel suit? not bad.
嗨 嗨 嗨 轻点
Hey, hey, hey. Easy, easy!
- 我已经很小心了 - 不 你是很粗重了
- I'm being very careful. - No, you're being very hulky.
- 我很小心的 - 这些是皮姆粒子好吗
- I'm being careful. - These are pym particles, all right?
汉克·皮姆消失了之后
And ever since hank pym got snapped…
就剩这么多了
Out of existence, this is it…
一共只有这么多 我们再也造不出来了
This is what we have. We're not making any more.
- 斯科特 冷静一点 - 抱歉
- Scott, calm down. - Sorry.
我们的量只够一人来回一次
We've got enough for one round trip, each.
就这么多 不能重来 外加两次测试
That's it. No do-overs. Plus, two test runs.
只剩一次了
One test run.
好吧 我还没做好准备
All right. I'm not ready for this.
好吧
OK.
我来
I'll do it.
克林特 你会因为时空转换
Clint, now you're gonna feel a little discombobulated…
而觉得有些混乱 别担心
From the chronoshift. Don't worry about it.
等下 我有个问题
Wait a second, let me ask you something.
如果我们可以 你知道
If we can do this, you know,
回到过去 为什么不
Go back in time, why don't we just…
找到小时候的灭霸 然后
Find baby thanos, you know? and…
- 首先 这太残忍了 - 那可是灭霸
- First of all, that's horrible. - It's thanos.
其次 时间不是这么运作的
And secondly, time doesn't work that way.
改变过去并不会改变未来
Changing the past doesn't change the future.
听着 我们回到过去
Look, we go back, we get the…
在灭霸拿到石头之前得到石头
Stones before Thanos gets them…
这样灭霸就没法拿到石头 问题解决了
Thanos doesn't have the stones. Problem solved.
- 没错 - 这行不通的
- Bingo. - That's not how it works.
- 我是这么听说的 - 什么
- Well, that's what I heard. - What?
谁 谁这么说的
By who? Who told you this?
星际迷航 终结者 时空特警 两世奇人
Star trek, terminator, timecop, time after time,
- 时光怪客 - 时间的褶皱
- Quantum leap. - A wrinkle in time,
- 时光倒流七十年 - 热浴盆时光机
- Somewhere in time, - Hot tub time machine.
阿比阿弟大冒险
Bill and ted's excellent adventure. Basically,
基本上所有和时间旅行有关的电影
Any movie that deals with time travel…
虎胆龙威 不 这个不算
Die hard? No, it's not…
人们都知道的
This is known.
我不知道为什么大家都相信这些
I don't know why everyone believes that…
但这不是真的
But that's not true…
想一想 如果你穿越到了过去 那么过去就变成了你的未来
Think about it. If you travel to the past, that past becomes your future.
那你之前的现在就成了过去
And your former present becomes the past.
这个过去不会被新的未来而改变
Which can't now be changed by your new future…
没错
Exactly.
所以《回到未来》只是一部胡编乱造的片子吗
So back to the future's a bunch of bullshit?
好了 克林特 倒数 三 二 一
All right, clint. We're going in 3… 2… 1…
库伯
Cooper?
- 我的耳机在哪 - 莱拉
- Where are my headphones? - Lila?
莱拉 不
Lila! no!
爸爸
Dad?
看着我 你还好吗
Hey, hey. Look at me. You Okay?
还好
Yeah.
成功了
It worked.
好了 我们有回去的方法了
Okay, so the "how" works.
现在就要弄清楚时间和地点了
Now we gotta figure out the "when, " and the "where."
这个房间里几乎所有人都
Almost everyone in this room has had an encounter…
见到过至少一颗无限宝石
With at least one of the six infinity stones.
或者可以把见过替换成
Well, I'd subtitute the word "encounter" for?
差点被某一颗弄死
Have been killed by one of the six infinity stones.
我没有 我甚至都不知道
I haven't. I don't even know what…
你们在说些什么
The hell you're talking about…
不管怎么说 我们的皮姆粒子
Regardless, we only have enough pym particles…
只够每人来回一趟
For one round trip each…
而且这些宝石曾出现在
And these stones have been in a lot of…
过去许多不同的地方
Different places through history…
在我们的过去 所以
Our history. So, not a lot of…
并没有很多合适的进入点
Convenient spots to drop in…
- 意味着我们要挑选合适的位置 - 没错
- Which means we have to pick our targets. - Correct.
所以 我们从以太开始吧
So. Let's start with the aether.
索尔 你知道些什么
Thor, what do you know?
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
不不
No, no.
很确定他死了
Pretty sure he's dead.
从哪开始说起呢
Where to start? umm…
首先 以太就不是一块宝石
The aether, first, is not a stone.
虽然以前有人说它长得像石头 呃
Someone's called it a stone before. Ahem…
但它更像是一团愤怒的泥巴
It's more of a… an angry sludge, sort of thing. So…
所以别管它叫宝石
Someone's gonna need to amend that, and stop saying that.
说来有趣
Here's an interesting story, though.
很多年前 为了不让黑暗精灵们发现
About the aether. My grandfather, many years ago,
我祖父不得不把以太藏起来
Had to hide the stone from the dark elves.
黑暗精灵是很吓人的 而简
Scary beings. So jane, actually…
就是她
Oh, there she is. That's jane…
我的前女友
She's… an old favor of mine.
有一次她把手伸进以太里
She… She stuck her hand inside a rock this one time…
然后以太就附在她身上了
And then the aether stuck itself inside her.
她变得很虚弱 我只好把她带回阿斯加德
And, she became very, very sick. So I had to take her to Asgard,
也就是我的家乡
Which is where I'm from.
我们努力想救她
And we had to try to fix her.
那时我们还在热恋
We were dating at the time, you see.
我将她介绍给我母亲
I got to introduce her to my, my mother.
现在我母亲死了
Who's dead, and umm…
简也不在我身边了
Oh, you know. Jane and I aren't even dating anymore, so…
世事就是这样的 没有什么天长地久
These things happen though, you know. Nothing lasts forever.
- 世上唯一 - 你先坐下休息会
- The only thing that… - Why don't you come sit down.
我还没说完呢
I'm not done yet.
世上唯一永恒的东西就是变化
The only thing thatis permanent in life is impermanent?
说得好
Awesome.
想吃点啥吗
Eggs? Breakfast?
我想喝杯血腥玛丽
No. I'd like a bloody mary.
奎尔说他是从魔拉格那偷走力量宝石的
Quill said he stole the power stone from Morag.
- 魔拉格是谁 - 魔拉格是个星球的名字
- Is that a person? - Morag's a planet.
奎尔才是人
Quill was a person.
星球 外太空的吗
Like a planet? like in outer space?
瞧瞧你 像只无忧无虑的
Oh, look. It's like a little puppy,
小狗狗
All happy there.
你想去太空吗 你想去太空吗 小狗狗
Do you wanna go to space? you wanna go to space, puppy?
我能带你去啊
I'll take you to space.
- 灭霸是在沃米尔找到的灵魂宝石 - 沃米尔又是啥
- Thanos found the soul stone on Vormir. - What is Vormir?
一个由亡灵支配的地方
A dominion of death, at the very…
在宇宙中心
Center of celes…
灭霸就在那里杀了我姐姐
It's where… Thanos murdered my sister.
记住了
Noted.
- 那个戴着时间宝石的家伙 - 奇异博士
- That time stone guy… - Doctor strange.
他是哪方面的博士啊
Yeah, what kind of doctor was he?
街头变戏法的那种
Neurostuff meets rabbit from a hat.
他住的可是黄金地段呢
Nice place in the village though.
- 对 住在苏利文街吧 - 不 应该是布里克街
- Yeah. Sullivan street. - Hmm… Bleecker.
什么 他也住在纽约吗
Wait, he lived in New York?
- 他住多伦多吧 - 没有 是苏利文街
- No. He lived in toronto. - Yeah,
不是布里克街
Not bleecker.
等等 如果你选对了时间
Guys, if you pick the right year,
会有三颗宝石同时出现在纽约
There are three stones in New York.
不是吧
Shut the front door!
好了 我们的计划是这样
All right. We have a plan.
六颗宝石 分三队人马 只有一次机会
Six stones, three teams, one shot.
五年前 我们输了
Five years ago, we lost.
我们都输了
All of us.
我们失去了朋友
We lost friends…
失去了家人
We lost family…
甚至失去了自我
We lost a part of ourselves.
今天 我们有机会夺回一切
Today, we have a chance to take it all back.
我们团队作战 只有一个任务
You know your teams, you know your missions.
拿到宝石 并带回来
Get the stones, get them back.
每人只能一次来回 不能犯错 也不能重来
One round trip each. No mistakes. No do-overs.
我们去的是记忆里熟悉的地方
Most of us are going somewhere we know.
但也可能会有突发情况
But it doesn't mean we should know what to expect.
注意安全 互相照应
Be careful. Look out for each other.
这是我们的命运之战 我们一定会赢
This is the fight of our lives. And we're gonna win.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
祝我们好运
Good luck.
- 他还挺会的 - 要你说
- He's pretty good at that. - Right?
行了 你们听到了吧
All right. You heard the man.
那就开始吧 同意吗
Stroke those key, y'all agree?
追踪器启动了
Tractors engaged.
你要保证把它完整带回来啊
You promise to bring that back in one piece, right?
好 好 好 行吧
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
- 我会尽力的 - 你这保证也太敷衍了
- I'll do my best. - As promises go, that was pretty lame.
一分钟后见
See you in a minute.
（纽约 2012年）
我们分头行动
All right, we all have our assignments.
两颗宝石在上城区 一颗在下城区
Two stones uptown, one stone down,
低调行事 注意时间
Stay low. Keep an eye on the clock.
你要不要也砸一下找找感觉
Maybe smash a few things along the way.
我觉得没必要 但试试也无妨
I think it's gratuitous, but whatever.
小心点 地板刚打了蜡
I'd be careful going that way. We just had the floors waxed.
我来找奇异博士
I'm looking for Doctor Strange.
你来早了五年
You're about… Five years too early.
史蒂芬·斯特兰奇现在
Stephen Strange is currently performing…
在离这里二十个街区的地方做手术呢
Surgery about twenty blocks that way.
你找他干什么
What do you want from him?
要那个 实际上
That, actually.
哦
Ah.
- 恐怕不行 - 对不起 我非拿不可
- I'm afraid not. - Sorry, but I wasn't asking.
- 你不想和我过招的 - 确实 我不想
- You don't wanna do this. - You're right. I don't.
但我需要这颗宝石 而且我没有时间了
But I need that stone, and I don't have time to…
我们从头来说 好吗
Let's start over, shall we?
（阿斯加德 2013年）
给您的 小姐
For you lady.
你们有裤子吗
Do you have pants?
裤子
Pants?
当我没说 这个就可以 谢谢你
Don't mind. It'll be fine. Thank you.
那就是简
That's Jane.
好了 我们这样做
All right. Here's the deal, puppy.
你去引诱她然后我
You're gonna charm her and I'm…
从后面给她来一下
Gonna poke her with this thing.
把现实宝石抽出来后我们就溜
And extract the reality stone and get gone, lickety-split.
我去去就来 那里有个
I'll be right back, Okay? There's a…
酒窖 就在这下面
Wine cellar, which is down here.
我父亲以前藏了很多酒在里面
My father used to stash with a huge barrel of ale.
我去看看能不能偷点来喝
I'll see if the cellar has a couple of…
喂 你还没喝够吗
Hey! aren't you drunk enough already.
- 你去给洛基送点汤吧 - 好的 夫人
- You can bring some soup to Loki. - Yes, ma'am.
那个时髦大妈是谁
Who's the fancy broad?
那是我母亲 她就是在今天死的
It's my mother. She dies today.
就是这一天啊
Oh. That's today?
我做不到 我做不到
I can't do this. I can't do this.
我不该在这的 我不该来的
I shouldn't be here. I shouldn't have come.
这个主意太糟了 我要失控了
This is a bad idea. I'm losing it.
- 过来 - 不 不 不 我
- Come here. - No, no, no. I'm having…
- 我喘不过气了 - 你过来 站这儿
- I'm having a panic attack. - Come here. Right here.
你以为只有你失去了亲人吗
You think you're the only one who lost people?
不然我们在这干啥
What do you think we're doing here?
我失去了唯一的家
I lost the only family I ever had.
奎尔 格鲁特 德拉克斯 有触角的姐们 他们都消失了
Quill, Groot, Drax, the chick with the antenna, all gone.
我知道你想妈妈了 但她已经死了 再也回不来了
Now, I get you miss your mom, but she's gone, really gone.
但还有其他很多的人可以被救回来
And there are plenty of people who are only kinda gone.
他们需要你的帮助
But you can help them.
所以你赶紧把脸收拾一下
So is it too much to ask that you brush the crumbs on your beard,
和那个小妞搭个讪
Make schmoopy talk to pretty pants,
然后趁她不注意
And when she's not looking,
把现实宝石吸出来帮我救回我的家人
Suck out the infinity stone and help me get my family back?
好
Okay.
- 你是在哭吗 - 没有
- Are you crying? - No…
对 我觉得自己失控了
Yes! I feel like I'm losing it.
振作起来 你可以的
Get it together! You can do this.
你可以的
You can do this.
好吗
All right?
- 好 我做得到 - 很好
- Yes, I can. - Good.
我做得到 我做得到
I can do this. I can do this.
我做不到啊
I can't do this.
好了 小可怜 她落单了 我们的机会来了
Alright, heartbreaker. She's alone. This is our shot.
人呢
Thor?
索尔
Thor!
（魔拉格 2014年）
好了 把它放下来吧 蓝蓝
Alright. Bring it down, blue.
沿着那条线 就是那里 继续放
Right on that line. That's it. Down, down.
能快点吗
Hey, can we hurry it up?
快点 我们赶时间啊
Guys, chop-chop. Come on. We're on the clock.
你们净是帮倒忙
All that, is really helpful.
- 注意安全 - 好
- Take care, Okay? - Yeah.
拿到石头赶紧回来 别搞砸了
Take that stone and come back. No messing around.
你可以的
You got this.
- 我们速战速决吧 - 好的
- Let's get it done. - Yes, sir.
回见
See you back.
你们互相照应啊
You guys watch each other's six.
嗯
Yeah.
沃米尔的坐标我已经输好了
The coordinates for Vormir are laid in.
只要他们会开飞船就没问题
All they have to do is not fall out.
这儿离布达佩斯也就十万八千里吧
We're a long way from Budapest.
那个
Okay, so, uhh…
我们只需要在这坐等那个叫奎尔的出现
We just wait around for this Quill guy to show up and…
然后让他带我们去能量宝石就好 对吧
Then he leads us to the power stone, is that it?
我们埋伏起来吧
Let's take cover.
2014年要找宝石的可不止我们
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
等下 你刚刚是什么意思
Wait a minute, what are you talking about right now?
还有谁在找这些宝石
Who else is looking for these stones?
我父亲 我姐姐
My father, my sister…
- 还有我 - 还有你
- And me. - And you?
你这时候在哪
Where are you right now?
- 不客气 - 我可没求你帮忙
- You're welcome. - I didn't ask for your help.
然而给你救场的总是我
And yet, you always need it.
起来
Get up.
- 父亲叫我们回飞船上 - 为什么
- Father wants us back on the ship. - Why?
他发现了一颗无限宝石
He's found an infinity stone.
- 在哪 - 一个叫魔拉格的星球
- Where? - On a planet called Morag.
父亲的计划终于启动了
Father's plan is finally in motion.
- 只是六分之一 星云 - 但这是个开始
- One stone isn't six, nebula. - It's a start.
如果他集齐全部
If he gets all of them…
罗南找到了力量宝石
Ronan's located the power stone.
我要派你们去他的飞船上
I'm dispatching you to his ship.
- 他会不情愿的 - 敢反抗就要他的命
- He won't like that. - His alternative is death, then.
罗南的执念蒙蔽了他的判断
Ronan's obsession clouds his judgement.
我们不会让您失望的 父亲
We will not fail you, father.
当然不会
No, you won't.
我发誓
I swear…
您会为我骄傲
I will make you proud.
我们就只需要等着这个叫奎尔的人出现
We just, wait around for this quill guy to show up,
让他带着我们去找力量宝石 是吗
And then he leads us to the power stone, is that it?
先埋伏好
Let's take cover.
2014年要找宝石的可不止我们
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
- 那是谁 - 我不知道
- Who was that? - I don't know…
我的头要裂开了 我不知道
My head is splitting… I don't know…
她的感官神经元在战斗中可能损坏了
Her synaptic drive was probably damaged in battle.
带她去我的飞船
Bring her to my ship.
得快点 队长 看起来
Got to hustle, cap. Things look like…
他们要收尾了
They're just about to…
收到 我正去电梯那里
Got it. I'm approaching the elevator now.
如果可以的话
If it's all the same to you…
我现在想喝那杯酒了
I'll have that drink now.
好了 让他起来
All right. Get him on the…
以后耍帅的机会多着呢
Stay around and posing up later.
还有 记得帮我收拾一下
By the way, if you're free to clean up.
罗杰斯先生 我差点忘了那件制服
Ugh, mr. Rogers. I almost forgot that that suit…
臀部设计真是不忍直视
Did nothing for your ass.
又没人要你看 托尼
No one asked you look, Tony.
- 太荒谬了 - 我觉得你看上去挺好 队长
- It's ridiculous. - I think you look great, cap.
在我看来 这就是经典的美国翘臀
As far as I'm concerned, that's america's ass.
魔杖应该交给谁
Who gets the… Magic wand?
神盾突击队来了
Strike team's coming here.
交给我们就可以了
We can take that off your hands.
你说了算
By all means.
小心点
Careful with that thing!
不然会被洗脑的
Unless you wanna mind erased.
- 这可不怎么好玩 - 我们会小心的
- Not in a fun way. - We promise to be careful.
- 这些人是谁 - 他们是神盾局
- Who are these guys? - They are shield…
实际上是九头蛇 但我们当时还不知道
Well, actually hydra. But, we didn't know that yet.
不是吧 你们不知道 他们一看就是坏人
Seriously, you didn't? I mean… They look like bad guys.
你长得小 话可不少
You're small, but you're talking loud.
搜索救援由我来指挥
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue!
说真的 你们怎么会认为
I mean, honestly! how do you think you'll be…
闭嘴
Shut up.
好了 上吧 小家伙 我们要的宝石就在那里
All right, you're up, little buddy. There's our stone.
好 把我弹出去
Alright. Flick me.
- 喂 喂 喂 - 嘿 伙计
- Whoa! whoa, whoa. - Hey! buddy.
你要干吗 已经超重了
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
- 走楼梯去 - 对 别进来
- Take the stairs! - Yeah. Stop. Stop!
讨厌楼梯 讨厌楼梯
Hate the stairs. Hate the stairs!
好了 队长 权杖在电梯里
All right, cap. I got our scepter in the…
刚过十八层
Elevator just passing the 18th floor.
来了
On it.
- 去大厅吧 - 好 大厅见
- Head to the lobby. - Alright. I'll see you there.
证物到手 正要与李斯特博士汇合
Evidence secure. We're in route to dr. List.
没有 没有任何阻碍 部长先生
No. No hitches at all, mr. Secretary.
队长 你不是去指挥搜救了吗
Captain. I thought you were coordinating search and rescue?
计划有变
Change of plans.
你好 队长
Hey, cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
我刚接到部长电话
I just got a call from the secretary.
现在由我来接手权杖
I'm gonna be running the scepter.
长官 你什么意思
Sir? I don't understand.
我们收到线报 有人要偷走它
We got word there may be an attempt to steal it.
抱歉 队长
Sorry, cap.
我们不能把权杖交给你
We can't give you the scepter.
我要给局长打个电话
I'm gonna have to call the director.
没问题的 相信我
It's ok, trust me.
九头蛇万岁
Hail hydra.
这么多楼梯
So many stairs!
拇指姑娘 能听见吗 我看到目标了
Thumbelina, do you copy? I've got eyes on the prize.
- 该上场了 - 已经出动了
- It is go-time. - Bombs away.
你用了什么香体喷雾吗
Is, is that axe body spray?
是的 我抽屉里放了一个以备不时之需
Yeah, I had a can just for emergencies. Relax.
- 能不能集中精神 - 我要进去了
- Can we focus, please? - I'm going inside you. Now.
请问你们要去哪里
May I ask you where you're going?
去吃中饭 回阿斯加德 抱歉 你是
To lunch and then asgard. I'm sorry, you are?
亚历山大·皮尔斯
Alexander pierce.
尼克·弗瑞的顶头上司
Who's the man of the folks of Nick Fury.
叫我部长先生就可以了
My friends call me Mr. Secretary.
你们得把犯人移交给我
I'm gonna have to ask you to turn that prisoner over to me.
洛基只能由奥丁亲自裁决
Loki will be answering to Odin himself.
他不能走
Oh, he's gonna answer to us…
奥丁可以拿走其他的 我只要那个箱子
Odin can have what's left. and I'm gonna need that case.
过去七十年里它一直是神盾局的财产
That's been shield property for over 70 years.
把箱子给我 史塔克
Hand over the case, stark.
好了 行动 精灵鼠小弟
All right, move it, stuart little.
情况有点失控了
Things are getting dict that was your job.
我不想争论现在
I'm not gonna argue who's got the…
谁说了算
Higher authority here.
你不会死掉吧
You promise me you won't die?
只会有一点心律失常
You're only giving me a mild cardiac dysrythmia.
听起来可不像只有一点
That doesn't sound mild.
把箱子给我
I need the case.
我知道你的权力很大 我只是说
I know you got a lotta pull. I'm just saying…
那就把箱子给我
Okay. Then give me the case.
动手 朗
Do it, lang!
- 把手松开 - 没时间了 拔掉插头
- Get your hands off! - Window's closing. Pull my pin!
就来
Here goes!
- 史塔克 - 史塔克
- Stark? - Stark!
他在抽搐 给他透透气
Look, he's convulsing. Give him air!
- 医护人员 - 医护人员
- Medic! - Medic!
有人需要帮助
This guy need some help!
史塔克 是你胸前机器的问题吗
Stark, you… Your chest machine?
呼吸 呼吸
Breathe! breathe!
干得好 在小巷等我
Good job. Meet me in the alley.
我吃点东西
I'm gonna grab that cube.
不要楼梯
No stairs!
你会没事的 史塔克 坚持住
You'll be fine, stark. Stay with us!
我要试一下 不知道有没有用
I'll try something, Okay? I have no idea if it's gonna work.
棒
Yes!
起作用了 真是疯狂
That worked a treat. That was so crazy!
我根本不知道能不能起作用
I had no idea if that was gonna work.
- 箱子 - 箱子
- The case… - The case. It's, uhh…
箱子呢 洛基呢
Where's the case? where's loki?
洛基
Loki!
- 本来可以不用这样的 - 我们搞砸了
- That wasn't supposed to happen, was it? - Oh, we blew it.
洛基
Loki!?
托尼 发生什么事了
Tony, what's going on?
告诉我你找到魔方了
Tell me you found that cube.
你不是在逗我吧
Oh, you gotta be shitting me.
我在十四楼找到洛基了
I have eyes on loki. 14th floor.
我不是洛基
I'm not loki.
我也不想伤害你
And I don't wanna hurt you.
我能打一整天
I can do this all day.
我知道 我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
你怎么会有这个
Where did you get this?
巴基 还活着
Bucky… Is… alive!
什么
What?
还真是美国翘臀
That is america's ass.
- 求你了 拜托 - 抱歉 我帮不了你 布鲁斯
- Please, please! - I'm sorry. I can't help you, bruce.
如果我把时间宝石交给你
If I give up the time stone to help…
去帮助你的现实 我的现实便会陷入危机
Your reality, I'm dooming my own.
无意冒犯 我认为
With all due respect, I'm not sure…
科学理论不是这样的
The science really support that.
无限宝石缔造了
The infinity stones create what you…
你们所经历的时间流
Experience as the flow of time.
拿走一颗宝石 时间便会分流
Remove one of the stones, and that flow splits.
这么做也许会帮助你的现实
Now this may benefit your reality.
但我这里的可就不一定了
But my new one not so much.
在这个新的现实分支里
In this new branched reality, without our…
没有对抗黑暗力量的主要武器
Chief weapon against the power of darkness,
我们的世界会危在旦夕 成千上万的人将会受苦受难
Our world will be overrun. Millions will suffer.
告诉我 博士 你的科学能阻止这一切吗
So, tell me, doctor, can your science prevent all that?
不能 但我们会消除它
No. But we can erase it.
一旦我们用完宝石
Because once we're done with the stones,
就会把它们归还到
We can return each one…
被拿走的那个时间点 所以 从时间线上来看
At the moment it was taken. So, chronologically…
在原来的现实里 宝石从没离开过
In that reality…. It never left.
不错 可你却忽略了最重要的一点
Yes, but you're leaving out the most important part.
想要归还宝石 你必须活下来
In order to return the stones, you have to survive.
我们会的 我会的 我保证
We will. I will. I promise.
我不能只为了一个保证就用我们的现实去冒险
I can't risk this reality on a promise.
至上尊者的职责就是
It's the duty, of the sorcerer…
保护时间宝石
Supreme to protect the time stone.
那为什么斯特兰奇把它交出去了
Then why the hell did strange give it away?
- 你说什么 - 斯特兰奇 他交出了宝石
- What did you say? - Strange. He gave it away.
他把宝石给了灭霸
He gave it to thanos.
- 他是自愿的吗 - 是的
- Willingly? - Yes.
- 为什么 - 我也不知道 也许他错了
- Why? - I have no idea. Maybe he made a mistake.
或者我错了
Or I did.
斯特兰奇是我们当中最优秀
Strange was meant to be the best of us.
所以他这么做一定有原因
So he must've done it for a reason.
你恐怕是对的
I fear you might be right.
谢谢
Thank you.
靠你了 布鲁斯
I'm counting on you, Bruce.
我们都靠你了
We all are.
运行检查程序
Run diagnostics.
给我看看她的记忆文件
Show me her memory file.
大人 记忆文件有点混乱
Sire, the file appears entangled.
确实是一段记忆 但不是她的
It was a memory, but not hers.
有另外一个意识在共享她的神经网络
There's another consciousnesssharing her network.
另一个星云
Another Nebula.
这不可能
Impossible.
这个复制品的时间戳 来自九年后的未来
This duplicate carries a time stamp… from nine years in the future.
那这另一个星云在哪
Where is this other Nebula?
在我们的星系里 在魔拉格上
In our solar system. On Morag.
- 你能接入她吗 - 可以 她们是互相连接的
- Can you access her? - Yes. The two are linked.
在这个复制品的记忆里 搜索无限宝石
Search the duplicate's memories, for Infinity Stones.
历史上这些宝石曾出现在很多不同的地方
And these stones have been in a lot of different places throughout history.
我们的历史上 所以 没有那么多地点可选
Our history. So, not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in.
- 这意味着我们需要谨慎选择目标 - 没错
- Which means we have to pick our targets. - Correct.
暂停影像
Freeze image.
地球人
Terrans.
复仇者
Avengers.
自命不凡的可怜虫 那个倒影是什么
Unruly wretches. What's that reflection?
把它放大 乌木喉
Amplify this, Maw.
我不明白
I don't understand.
- 两个星云 - 不 是同一个星云
- Two Nebulas. - No. The same Nebula.
来自两个不同的时间
From two different times.
设置好去魔拉格的航线 继续扫描这个复制品的记忆
Set course for Morag. Scan the duplicate's memories.
我想看到一切
I want to see everything.
女士们 待会见 走吧
My ladies, I'll see you after. Go on.
- 你在干什么呢 - 啊
- What are you doing? - Ahh!
偷偷摸摸的事还是让你弟弟来吧
You're better off leaving the sneaking to your brother.
我只是正好在散步 然后
Yeah, I was simply just going for a walk, and uh…
你穿的这是什么
What are you wearing?
我一直这么穿 这件是我的最爱之一
I always wear this. This is one of my favorites.
你的眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with your eye?
喔 我的眼睛 那是 你还记得哈罗金之战吗
Oh, my eye. That's… You remember the Battle of Haroquin?
那时我被阔剑砍中了脸
When I got hit in the face with a broadsword?
你根本不是我认识的那个索尔 对吗
You're not the Thor I know at all, are you?
不 我是
Yes, I am.
你在未来受了很多苦吧
The future hasn't been kind to you, has it?
我可没说我是从未来来的
I didn't say I'm from the future.
孩子 我是被女巫养大的
I was raised by witches, boy.
我可不止用眼睛在看 你知道的
I see with more than eyes, and you know that.
我确实 确实来自未来
I am totally, totally from the future!
是啊 孩子
Yes, you are.
- 我真的想和你说说话 - 慢慢来
- I really need to talk to you. - We can talk.
他的头在这边
His head was over there…
他的身体在那边
His body over there…
但是又有什么意义呢 已经太迟了
What was the point. I was too late.
我只是站在那
I was just standing there.
- 就是个拿着斧子的傻子 - 你才不是傻子
- Some idiot with an ax. - You're no idiot.
你不是来到了这里吗 向阿斯加德最睿智的人求助
You're here aren't you? Seeking counsel from the wisest person in Asgard.
- 我想可以这么说 - 傻子 算不上
- I guess, yeah. - Idiot? No.
- 但失败是肯定的 - 这话就不太好听了
- A failure? Absolutely. - That's a little bit harsh.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You do know what that makes you?
意味着和其他所有人一样
Just like everyone else.
但是我不应该和其他人一样 不是吗
I'm not supposed to be like everyone else, am I?
每个人在追寻自己应该成为的样子时都会经历失败 索尔
Everyone fails at who they are supposed to be, Thor.
衡量一个人 一个英雄的标准
The measure of a person, of a hero…
是他们最终接受并成就自我
Is how well they succeed at being who they are.
我真的很想你 妈妈
I really missed you, Mum.
索尔 我拿到了
Thor! I got it!
抓住那只兔子
Get that rabbit!
- 妈妈 我有些事必须告诉你 - 不 儿子 不需要
- Ma, I have to tell you something. - No, son. You don't.
你来这里要拯救的是你的未来 不是我的
You're here to repair your future, not mine.
- 但这和你的未来有关 - 与我无关
- But this is about your future. - It's none of my business.
你好
Hey.
你肯定就是他母亲了
You must be Mom.
我拿到东西了 我们得赶紧撤了
I got the thing. Come on, we got to move.
- 真想陪你多待一会 - 不 这已经是馈赠了
- I wish we had more time. - This was a gift.
快去成就你自己吧
And you're going to be the man you're meant to be.
- 我爱你 妈妈 - 我也爱你
- I love you, Mom. - I love you.
多吃点沙拉吧
And eat a salad.
- 快点 我们该走了 - 再见
- Come on. We gotta go. - Goodbye.
- 三 二 - 不 等等
- Three… Two… - No, wait!
又怎么了
Wh… What am I looking at?
喔 有时候是要花点时间
Oh, sometimes it takes a second.
我仍然配得上它
I'm still worthy.
真是够了
Oh, boy.
再见 妈妈
Goodbye, Mom.
他是个傻子吧
So he's an idiot?
确实
Yeah.
那是什么
What's that?
盗贼的工具
The tool of a thief.
这时候是不是该有尖刺冒出来 上面挂着骷髅什么的
This is the part where spikes come out, with skeletons on the end and everything…
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
一个叫力量宝石神庙的地方
When you break into a place called the temple of the Power Stone,
一定会有很多陷阱 好吧 走吧
There's gonna be a bunch of booby traps… Okay. All right. Go ahead.
我以前不是这样的
I wasn't always like this.
我也不是
Me either.
但这样的身体对我们来说也有用 不是吗
But we work with what we got, right?
同步开始
Sync up.
三 二 一
Three.. Two.. One…
你杀害了无数生命
You murdered trillions!
你们应该感激
You should be grateful.
- 宝石在哪里 - 没了
- Where are the stones? - Gone.
- 化为原子了 - 你两天前才刚刚用过
- Reduced to atoms. - You used them two days ago.
我用宝石摧毁了宝石 几乎也要了我的命
I used the stones to destroy the stones. It nearly killed me.
但我的使命完成了 注定如此
But the work is done. It always will be.
我 就是天命
I am inevitable.
- 你对他们做了什么 - 什么都没做 目前没有
- What did you do to them? - Nothing. Yet.
他们不是要阻止此时此刻我要做的事情
They're not trying to stop something I'm going to do in our time.
他们是要逆转那时候我已经完成的事
They're trying to undo something I've already done in theirs.
宝石
The stones…
我全部找齐了
I found them all.
我赢了
I won.
宇宙的天平达到了平衡
Tipped the cosmic scales to balance.
这就是您的未来
This is your future.
这是我的宿命
It's my destiny.
我的父亲什么都做得出来 但他从不说谎
My father is many things. A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你 女儿
Thank you, Daughter.
也许我对你太苛刻了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly…
我完成了我的宿命
And that, is destiny fulfilled.
大人 你的女儿
Sire, your Daughter…
不
No…
是个背叛者
is a traitor.
那不是我 那不是 我永远不能 我永远不会背叛您 永远
That's not me. It's not. I could never… I would never betray you. Never.
我知道
I know.
你马上就有机会证明这一点了
And you'll have the chance to prove it.
不
No…
他知道了
He knows!
巴顿 巴顿 快接听
Barton? Barton, come in.
罗曼诺夫 快接听 我们有麻烦了 拜托
Romanoff? Come in, we have a problem. Come on!
快接听 我们有麻
Come in, we have a prob….
灭霸知道了
Thanos knows.
灭霸
Thanos…
队长
Cap…
抱歉 伙计 我们有麻烦了
Sorry, buddy. We got a problem.
是有点麻烦
Huh. Yeah, we do.
- 我们现在要做什么 - 让我缓缓 史蒂夫
- Well, what are we gonna do now? - You know what, give me a break, Steve.
我刚刚被浩克砸中了脑袋
I just got hit in the head with a Hulk.
你说过我们只有一次机会 那就是我们的唯一机会
You said that we had one shot. This, this was our shot.
我们用了 就没得用了 凑不齐就白费 凑不齐就白费
We shot it. It's shot. Six stones or nothing. Six stones or nothing.
你在重复自己的话 你知道吗 你在重复你自己
You're repeating yourself, you know that? You're repeating yourself.
你才在重复自己的话 你才在重复自己的话
You're repeating yourself. You're repeating yourself.
- 不 - 拜托
- No! - Come on.
你根本不想搞时空劫持 你后来接受了时空劫持
You never wanted a time heist, you went on board with the time heist…
- 我搞砸了 - 你最后毁了时空劫持
- I dropped the ball. - You ruined the time heist.
- 怪我吗 - 是啊
- Is that what I did? - Yeah!
还有什么办法能搞到宇宙魔方吗
Are there any other options with the Tesseract?
没有了 没其他办法了
No, no, no. There's no other options.
没有重来的机会 我们哪里也去不了
There's no do-overs. We're not going anywhere else.
我们每人只有一管粒子 一管
We have one particle left. Each.
就是这样 明白吗 我们要是用了 再见 你们别想回家了
That's it, alright? We use that… Bye, bye. You're not going home.
可是如果我们不尝试一下
Yeah, well if we don't try…
那所有人也都回不了家
Then no one else is going home, either.
我知道了
I got it.
还有一个办法 能重新拿到宇宙魔方并且拿到新的粒子
There's another way. To retake the Tesseract and acquire new particles.
我们在回忆的小路上多走几步
We'll stroll down memory lane.
新泽西军事基地
Military Installation…
什么时候可以在那儿同时找到这两样东西
When were they both there?
它们同时在那里是在 我隐约记得一个时间
They were there at a… I've a vaguely exact idea.
有多隐约
How vague?
你们在说什么 我们要去哪
What are you talking about? where are we going?
- 我确定它们在那里 - 他们是谁
- I know for a fact they were there… - Who's they?
- 我们要去做什么 - 我也知道我为什么知道
- What are we doing? - And I know how I know.
伙计们 怎么了 你们在说什么
Guys, what's up? what is it?
看上去我们要即兴发挥一下了
Well, it looks like we're improvising.
- 好 - 我们要即兴发挥什么
- Great. - What are we improvising?
斯考特 把这个带回去
Scott, get this back to the compound.
准备
Suit up.
新泽西有什么
What's in new jersey?
- 04-04 - 07
- 0-4, 0-4… - Uhh, 0-7.
- 07 - 打扰一下
- 0-7. - Excuse me…
1-9-7-0.
- 你确定吗 - 队长 队长 史蒂夫 不好意思
- Are you sure? - Cap. Captain. Steve, sorry.
美国 罗杰斯 听着 如果你们这么做
America. Rogers. Look, if you do this,
最后没有成功 你们就回不来了
And this doesn't work, you're not coming back.
谢谢你的鼓舞 小家伙
Thanks for the pep talk, pissant.
你相信我吗
You trust me?
相信
I do.
等你下令
Your call.
出发
Here we go.
（新泽西州 1970年）
嘿 伙计们
Hey, man!
床上去吧 不要打仗
Make love, not war!
（美国军队）
你肯定不是真的出生在这儿的 对吧
Clearly, you weren't actually born here, right?
创造我的想法诞生在这儿
The idea of me was.
好吧 假设你是神盾局
Right. Well, imagine you're shield, running a…
想组织一个法西斯情报机构
Quasi-fascistic intelligence organization.
你会把它藏在哪里
Where do you hide it?
众目睽睽之下
In plain sight.
祝你任务顺利 队长
Good luck on your mission, captain.
也祝你 项目成功 博士
Good luck on your project, doctor.
你是新来的吗
You're new here?
不算是
Not exactly.
找到了
Gotcha.
重返赛场
Back in the game.
阿尼姆 你在这儿吗
Arnim, you in there?
阿尼姆
Arnim?
嘿
Hey!
门在这边 伙计
The door's this way, pal.
哦 对
Oh, yeah.
我在找佐拉博士 你看到他了吗
I'm looking for dr. Zola. Have you seen him?
嗯 没有 佐拉博士 我谁也没看到
Yeah, no, dr. Zol… No, I haven't seen a soul.
不好意思
Pardon me.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
不 先生 我
No, sir. I'm, a…
是麻省理工学院来的访客
Visitor from mit.
啊 麻省理工
Huh. Mit.
你叫
Got a name?
霍华德
Howard.
这倒是很好记
Well that'll be easy to remember.
霍华德
Howard…
波兹
potts.
好吧 我是霍华德 史塔克
Well, I'm howard stark.
你好
Hi.
握个手 别使劲扯
Shit. Now, don't pull it.
对
Yeah…
波兹 你看上去脸色很苍白啊
You look a little green around the gills there, potts.
我没事 就是累了
I'm fine. Just, long hours.
想出去呼吸点新鲜空气吗
Wanna get some air?
- 波兹 你在听吗 - 好 那再好不过了
- Hello, potts. - Yeah. That would be swell.
- 这边走 - 好的
- That way. - Okay.
别忘了你的手提箱
Need your briefcase?
你不是那些披头士吧 波兹
You're not one of those beatles, are ya, potts?
- 你好 - 皮姆博士
- Hello. - Dr. Pym?
是的 你没有打错
That would be the number that you called. Yes.
我是史蒂夫队长 货运队的
This is capt. Stevens from shipping.
- 我们这儿有个您的包裹 - 带上来吧
- We have a package for you. - Bring it up.
问题是我们拿不上去 先生
Well, that's the thing, sir. We can't.
我糊涂了 这不是你们的工作吗
I'm confused. I thought that was your job.
是的 只是 先生 这个盒子在发光 而且
Well, it's just… Sir, the box is glowing and,
说实话 我们的一些
To be honest, some of our mail…
邮递员不太舒服
Guys aren't feeling that great…
他们没有打开箱子吧
They didn't open it, did they?
嗯 他们打开了 您最好快点下来
Yeah, they did. You better get down here.
不好意思 让一下
Excuse me. Out of the way!
所以 鲜花和泡菜罐头 你今晚有约吗
So, flowers and sauerkraut. You got a big date tonight?
我妻子怀孕了
My wife's expecting.
而且 我最近工作得太多了
And, uh… Too much time in the office.
- 恭喜 - 谢谢 帮我拿一下好吗
- Congratulations. - Thanks. Hold this, ?
没问题
Yeah, sure.
- 她怀孕多久了 - 我不知道
- How far along is she? - I don't know… Uh…
她现在处于
She's at the point where she can't…
受不了我咀嚼声的阶段
Stand the sound of my chewing…
我猜我又要在储藏室吃晚饭了
I guess I'll be eating dinner in the pantry again.
我有个小女儿
I have a little girl.
女儿不错
A girl would be nice. Less of a chance…
像我的机率要小些
She'd turn out exact like me…
像你不好吗
What'd be so awful about that?
我这个人说好听点就是
Let's just say that the greater good has rarely outweighed…
相对于集体利益更看重个人利益
My own self-interests.
你之前从没有见过这两个人吗
And you've never seen these 2 men before?
没有 我只是直觉
No, I've got ander all this.
- 他们很可疑 - 你能描述一下他们的样子吗
- The 2 of them looked fishy. - Can you describe them?
嗯 一个留着嬉皮士风格的胡子
Well, one of them had a hippie beard.
嬉皮士 像比吉斯还是蒙哥杰瑞
Hippie? Like bee gees or Mungo Jerry…
绝对是蒙哥杰瑞
Definitely mungo jerry.
我是切斯勒 我需要所有人员
Yeah, this is chesler. I need every available mps…
前往地下六层 我们可能被入侵了
On sub-level 6. We have a potential breach.
（玛格丽特·卡特 局长）
所以 你起好名字了吗
So, where are you at with names?
嗯 如果是个男孩 我妻子想叫他艾蒙佐
Well, if it's a boy, my wife likes almanzo.
或许你该趁着还有时间再仔细想想
Might wanna let that stew while you got time.
我想问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
当你的孩子出生的时候
When your kid was born…
- 你紧张吗 - 非常紧张
- Were you nervous? - Wildly. Yeah.
你觉得你能当好父亲吗
Did you feel qualified?
就是你知道
Like you had any idea how to…
怎么去正确地做这件事吗
Successfully operate that thing?
我还真的把每件事都考虑了
I literally pieced it together as I went along,
我想了一遍我父亲都做过些什么
I thought about what my dad did, and…
我爸 从来都
My old man, he never met a problem…
只用皮带解决问题
He couldn't solve with a belt…
我从前也觉得我父亲对我很严厉
I thought my dad was tough on me.
但是现在回想起来 我只
And now, looking back, I just…
记得那些好的事
Remember the good…
- 他的确字字珠玑 - 是吗 比如说
- He did drop the odd pearl. - Yeah? like what?
寸金难买寸光阴
"no amount of money ever bought a second of time."
聪明人
Smart guy.
他尽力了
He did his best.
跟你说实话吧 虽然这孩子还没有出生
Let me tell you. That kid's not even here yet…
但是我愿意为他做任何事
And, there's nothing I wouldn't do for him.
很高兴遇见你 波兹
Good to meet you, potts.
我也是 霍华德
Yeah, howard…
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be all right.
谢谢你做的一切
Thank you for everything…
对国家贡献
you've done for this country.
贾维斯
Jarvis.
我们以前见过这个人吗
Have we ever met that guy?
您见过的人太多了 先生
You meet a lot of people, sir.
感觉很熟悉
Seems very familiar.
不过胡子怪怪的
Weird beard, though.
- 你太弱了 - 我就是你
- You're weak. - I'm you.
你可以阻止这一切的
You can stop this.
你知道你想这么做
You know you want to.
你看到未来的发生了什么吗
Did you see what happens in the future?
灭霸找到了灵魂宝石
Thanos finds the soul stone.
你想知道他是怎么找到的吗
You wanna know how he does that?
你想知道 他对你做了什么吗
You wanna know, what he does to you?
够了
That's enough.
你让我恶心
You disgust me.
但你也不是完全没用
But, that doesn't mean you're useless.
我看上去如何
How do I look?
（沃弥尔 2014年）
哇哦
Wow…
要不是任务紧急
Under different circumstances,
这儿真的是个好地方
This would be totally awesome.
我猜浣熊他们不用爬山
I bet the raccoon didn't have to climb a mountain.
严格地说 他不是浣熊 你知道吧
Technically, he's not a raccoon, you know.
管他的 反正他也吃垃圾
Whatever. He eats garbage.
欢迎
Welcome.
娜塔莎 伊凡之女
Natasha, daughter of ivan.
克林特 伊迪丝之子
Clint, son of edith.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是向导
Consider me a guide.
你们的向导 所有想要找到灵魂宝石的人的向导
To you, and to all who seek the soul stone.
好的 那你告诉我们它在哪 我们拿了就走
Okay. You tell us where it is. Then we'll be on our way.
如果这么简单就好了
If only it were that easy.
你们要找的 就在你们面前
What you seek lies in front of you…
你们的恐惧也会随它而来
as does what you fear.
宝石在下面
The stone is down there.
对你们中的一个来说是宝石
For one of you.
对另一个人
For the other…
想要得到宝石
In order to take the stone,
你必须舍弃你爱的人
You must lose that which you love…
永恒的交易
An everlasting exchange.
灵魂 才能换灵魂
A soul, for a soul.
怎么样了
How's it going?
天哪
Jesus…
没准全都是他胡扯的
Maybe he's making this shit up.
不 我觉得不是
No. I don't think so.
为什么 就因为他知道你爸的名字
Why, 'cause he knows your daddy's name?
我都不知道我爸的名字
I didn't.
灭霸从这里离开的时候带走了宝石
Thanos left here with the stone…
但没带走他的女儿 这可不是巧合
Without his daughter. It's not a coincidence.
是
Yeah.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
如果我们不拿到宝石 亿万人就不可能活过来
If we don't get that stone, billions of people stay dead.
我知道
I know…
那我想我们都知道谁该去
Then I guess we both know who it's gotta be.
我想我们都知道
I guess we do.
我觉得
I'm starting to think…
我们俩的人选可能不太一样 娜塔莎
We mean different people here, Natasha.
过去五年 我只有一个目标
Last five years, I've been trying to do one thing.
就是来到这里
Get to right here.
这一切就是为了把所有人带回来
That's all it's been about bringing everybody back.
别跟我说什么漂亮话
Oh, don't you get all decent on me now.
你以为我想这么做吗
What, do you think I wanna do it?
我是在拯救你的性命 笨蛋
I'm trying to save your life, your idiot.
我不想让你这么做 因为我
Yeah well, I don't want you to, because i…
娜塔莎 你知道我曾经犯了什么错
Natasha, you know what I've done.
你知道我变成了什么
You know what I've become.
我从不用过错来评判一个人
I don't judge people on their worst mistakes.
也许你应该这样做
Maybe you should.
你都没有这样做
You didn't.
我真拿你没办法 你知道吗
You're a pain in my ass, you know that?
好吧
Okay.
你赢了
You win.
告诉我的家人 我爱他们
Tell my family I love them.
你自己说
You tell them yourself.
该死
Damn you!
等等
Wait…
放手吧
Let me go.
不
No.
求你了 别
Please, no.
没关系的
It's Okay.
求你了
Please…
拿到所有宝石了吗
Did we get them all?
我们居然成功了吗
You telling me this'll actually work?
克林特 娜塔莎呢
Clint, where's nat?
她有家人吗
Do we know if she had family?
有 我们
Yeah. Us.
什么
What?
我只是问了他一个问题
I just asked him a question…
是 但你说的好像她死了一样
Yeah, you're acting like she's dead.
为什么我们要当作她死了一样
Why are we acting like she's dead?
我们有宝石 不是吗
We have the stones, right? as long as we have…
只要我们有宝石 我们就能把她带回来 是不是
The stones, cap, we can bring her back, isn't that right?
所以别废话了 我们是复仇者 打起精神来
So stop this shit. We're the avengers, get it together.
我们不可能让她复活了
We can't get her back.
- 什 什么 - 这是不可逆转的 不可能的
- Wha… What? - It can't be undone. It can't.
不好意思 无意冒犯
I'm sorry. No offense,
但你只是一个地球人
But you're a very earthly being.
我们说的是宇宙魔法
We're talking about space magic.
不可能似乎太绝对了 你不觉得吗
And "can't" seems very definitive, don't you think?
我知道这件事我没有发言权
Look, I know that I'm way outside my paygrade here.
但是她依然回不来
But she still isn't here, is she?
- 不 我不这么觉得 - 这一切是不可逆转的
- No, that's my point. - It can't be undone.
至少那个飘着的红色的家伙是这么说的
Or that's at least what the red floating guy had to say.
也许你可以去问他 好吗
Maybe you wanna go talk to him? Okay?
拿上你的锤子 飞过去问他啊
Go grab your hammer, and you go fly and you talk to him.
本该是我的
It was supposed to be me.
她为了那块该死的石头牺牲了自己
She sacrificed her life for that goddamned stone.
这是她用命换来的
She put her life on it.
她回不来了
She's not coming back.
我们不能辜负她 一定不能
We have to make it worth it. We have to.
我们不会辜负她的
We will.
嘣
Boom!
好了 手套准备好了
All right. The glove's ready.
问题是 谁来打那个要命的响指呢
Question is, who's gonna snap their freaking fingers?
我来
I'll do it.
- 你说什么 - 没问题的
- Excuse me? - It's Okay.
- 不不不 停 - 等等
- No, no, no, no. Stop. Stop. - Hey, hey…
索尔 等一下
Thor, just wait.
我们还没决定谁来戴这个手套呢
We haven't decided who's gonna put that on yet.
不好意思你说什么 难道我们就
I'm sorry. What, were you just sitting…
坐在这儿等良辰吉日吗
Around waiting for the right opportunity?
至少我们应该讨论一下
We should at least discuss it.
听着 我们就这样坐在这儿 盯着那个玩意儿
Look, us sitting here staring at…
是不可能把所有人救回来的
That thing is not gonna bring everybody back…
我是最强的复仇者 好吗
I'm the strongest avenger, Okay?
所以这个责任必须落在我身上
So this responsibility falls on me.
- 这是我的使命 - 不是 - 别说了 就让我来
- It's my duty. - It's not that… - It's… Stop it! just let me.
让我来吧 就让我做点好事
Just let me do it. Just let me do something good.
- 做点正确的事 - 听着
- Something great. - Look…
不让你来 不仅是因为
It's not just the fact that that glove is channeling…
这个手套聚集着惊天动地的能量 我告诉你
Enough energy to light up a continent, I'm telling you…
你现在的状态不好
You're in no condition.
你觉得我血液里流淌的是什么东西
What do you think is coursing through my veins right now?
奶酪酱
Cheez whiz?
- 是闪电啊 - 是
- Lightning. - Yeah.
闪电也帮不了你 兄弟
Lightning won't help you, pal.
必须得是我
It's gotta be me.
你们也看见宝石让灭霸变成了那样
You saw what those stones did to Thanos.
这个响指几乎要了他的命
It almost killed him.
你们都扛不住的
None of you could survive.
那我们怎么确定你能扛得住
How do we know you will?
不确定 但是宝石的辐射主要是伽玛射线
We don't. But the radiation's mostly gamma.
就好像
It's like…
这就是我存在的意义
I was made for this.
准备好了吗
Good to go, yeah?
开始吧
Let's do it.
记住五年前所有被灭霸的响指变消失了的人
You remember everyone thanos snapped away five years ago…
把他们带回到现在 就是今天
And just bringing them back to now, today.
不要改变过去五年内任何的事情
Don't change anything from the last five years.
知道了
Got it.
星期五 启动防御程序
Friday, do me a favor and activate protocol 8.
好的 老板
Yes, boss.
所有人都回家吧
Everybody comes home.
- 摘下来 快摘下来 - 不 等等 布鲁斯 你还好吗
- Take it off. Take it off! - No, wait. Bruce, are you Okay?
说句话 班纳
Talk to me, banner.
没事 我没事
I'm Okay. I'm Okay.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
别动他
Don't move him.
- 成功了吗 - 不知道 好了 没事了
- Did it work? - Worth a shot. It's over. It's Okay.
（劳拉 来电）
- 亲爱的 - 克林特
- Honey. - Clint…
亲爱的
Honey.
各位
Guys…
我觉得 成功了
I think it worked!
我喘不过气了 喘不过气了 喘不过气了
I can't breathe. I can't breathe! I can't breathe.
战甲解除 战甲解除 战甲解除
Canopy. Canopy. Canopy.
罗德 火箭 快出来
Rhodey, rocket, get outta here!
救我出去 救我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
快点
Come on!
罗德
Rhodey!
呼叫救援 呼叫救援 有人吗
Mayday, mayday! does anybody copy?
我们在底层 这里进水了
We're in the lower here. It's flooding.
- 什么 - 我们快被淹死了 有人吗 救命
- What? - We're drowning! does anybody copy? mayday!
等等 我在 我在 能听到吗
Wait! I'm here! I'm here, can you hear me?
队长
Cap?
女儿
Daughter.
在 父亲
Yes, father.
所以这里就是未来 做得好
So, this is the future. Well done.
谢谢您 父亲 他们一点也没有怀疑
Thank you, father. They suspected nothing.
因为他们自以为是
The arrogant never do.
去吧
Go.
找到宝石 带回来给我
Find the stones. Bring them to me.
您要做什么
What will you do?
等待
Wait.
告诉我
Tell me something.
在未来 我们之间发生了什么
In the future, what happens to you and me?
我试图杀了你
I tried to kill you.
好几次
Several times.
但是最后 我们成了朋友
But eventually, we become friends.
我们成了姐妹
We become sisters.
来吧
Come on.
我们可以阻止他
We can stop him.
快点 兄弟 醒醒
Come on, buddy. Wake up.
这就对了
That's my man.
如果你再把这个丢了 我就不给你了
You lose this again, I'm keeping it.
怎么回事
What happened?
你搞时间 时间也会搞你
We messed with time. It tends to mess back.
你马上就懂了
You'll see.
他在做什么
What's he been doing?
什么也没做
Absolutely nothing.
宝石在哪儿
Where are the stones?
应该还在下面
Lost somewhere under all this.
总之他还没得手
All I know is he doesn't have them.
那就保证让他一直拿不到
So we keep it that way.
- 你知道这是个陷阱吧 - 知道
- You know it's a trap, right? - Yeah…
但我不在乎
I don't much care.
行
Good.
只要我们达成一致
Just as long as we're all in agreement.
这次就让我们彻底了结他
Let's kill him properly this time.
你接受不了失败
You could not live with your own failure.
最后怎么着
Where did that bring you?
还不是要面对我
Back to me.
我以为毁掉半数生命
I thought by eliminating half of life,
另一半会繁荣发展
The other half would thrive.
结果证明 那根本不可能
But you've shown me, that's impossible.
只要有人还记得过往
And as long as there are those that remember what was,
那就总会有
There will always be those that…
那些无法接受改变的人
Are unable to accept what can be.
他们会一直反抗
They will resist.
没错 我们就是那么固执
Yep. We're all kinds of stubborn.
我很感激
I'm thankful.
因为此时 我知道我必须做什么了
Because now, I know what I must do.
我要将这个宇宙化为尘埃
I will shred this universe down to its last atom.
之后
And then…
用你们帮我收集的宝石 创造全新的宇宙
With the stones you've collected for me, create a new one.
在那里全是
Teeming with life,
不念落失
That knows not what it has lost…
只认所得的生命
But only what it is been given.
一个懂得感恩的宇宙
A grateful universe.
由鲜血建立的宇宙
Born out of blood.
但他们无从得知
They'll never know it.
因为你们活不到那一天
Because you won't be alive to tell them.
下面见了兄弟
See you on the other side, man.
撑住 我来了
Hang on! I'm coming!
嗨
Oh, hey…
我认识你
I know you.
父亲 我拿到宝石了
Father. I have the stones.
什么
What?!
住手
Stop.
你要背叛我们吗
You're betraying us?
你没必要这么做的
You don't have to do this.
我必须这么做
I am… This.
不 不是这样的
No, you're not.
你看见我们变成什么样了
You've seen what we become.
星云 听她说
Nebula, listen to her.
你可以改变的
You can change.
他不会允许的
He won't let me.
别
No!
好了 索尔 给我来一下
Okay, thor. Hit me.
老板 醒醒
Boss, wake up.
我就知道
I knew it!
我这些年的征服
In all my years of conquest…
暴力
Violence…
杀戮
Slaughter…
从来不为了自己
It was never personal.
但我现在要让你们知道
But I'll tell you now…
我要怎么对付你们这个顽固不化
What I'm about to do to your stubborn,
令人烦厌 微不足道的星球
Annoying little planet…
我会非常 非常享受的
I'm gonna enjoy it. Very, very much.
队长 能听见我说话吗
Cap, you hear me?
队长 我是山姆 能听见我说话吗
Cap, It's sam. Can you hear me?
看左边
On your left.
必胜
所有人都到了吗
Is that everyone?
怎么 你还嫌不够吗
What, you wanted more?
复仇者们
Avengers…
集结
assemble.
不 不 那个给我
No, no. Give me that.
你拿小的
You have the little one.
喂
Hey!
我天
Holy cow.
你肯定不相信发生了什么
You will not believe what's been going on.
你还记得我们在太空里吗
Do you remember we were on space…
然后我化成灰了 我肯定昏过去了
And I got all dusty? I must've passed out,
我醒来后你就就不见了
'cause I woke up, you were gone.
但是奇异博士还在那里对吧 他好像说
But doctor strange was there, right? he was like,
已经过了五年了 快点 他们需要我们
"It's been five years. Come on, they need us!"
然后他就操控起了那个
And then he started doing the yellow…
金光闪闪的东西 把我们都带回来了
Sparkly thing that heou back here, Okay?
你怎么了
What are you doing?
感觉真好
This is nice.
卡魔拉
Gamora?
我以为我失去你了
I thought I lost you.
别碰我
Don't… Touch… Me!
第一脚没踢着
You missed the first time…
第二脚踢得可准
Then you got them both the second time.
就是他吗 不会吧
This is the one? seriously?
只能选他 或者一棵树了
The choices were him, or a tree.
队长 这东西怎么办
Cap, what do you want me to do with this damn thing?
有多远拿多远
Get those stones as far away as possible!
不行
No!
我们得把它们送回原来的地方
We need to get them back where they came from.
送不回去了
No way to get them back.
灭霸把量子通道毁了
Thanos destroyed the quantum tunnel.
等等
Hold on!
不止那一个时光机器
That wasn't our only time machine.
有谁看到一辆丑了吧唧的棕色面包车了吗
Anyone see an ugly brown van out there?
看见了
Yes!
但停的地方真不怎么样
But you're not gonna like where it's parked.
斯科特 你启动它要多久
Scott, how long you need to get that thing working?
大概十分钟
Maybe ten minutes.
那快去吧 我们把宝石带过去
Get it started. We'll get the stones to you.
好的 队长
We're on it, cap.
嘿
Hey.
你说我们有一千四百万分之一的几率能赢对吧
You said one out of 14 million, we win, yeah?
是这次吧
Tell me this is it.
如果我说了 就不会是了
If I tell you what happens, it won't happen.
希望你是对的
You better be right.
这里乱成一团了
It's a mess back here.
启动不了
It's… It's dead.
- 什么 - 启动不了
- What? - It's dead.
只能硬来了
I have to hotwire it.
星云在哪儿
Where's nebula?
她没回应
She's not responding.
大人
Sire!
克林特
Clint!
交给我
Give it to me.
你夺走了我的一切
You took everything from me.
我根本不知道你是谁
I don't even know who you are.
那就见识一下
You will.
拿到了
I got it!
启动一击必杀模式
Activate instant kill!
炮火压制
Rain fire!
但是大人 我们的部队
But sire, our troops!
按我说的做
Just do it!
有人注意到这个了吗
Is anyone else seeing this?
我能搞定
I got this.
I got this!
好吧 我搞不定
Okay, I don't got this.
- 救命啊 谁来帮帮我 - 皇后区的小子 抬头
- Help! somebody, help! - Hey, Queens. Heads up.
撑住 我来帮你了孩子
Hang on. I got you, kid.
你好 很高兴见到
Hey! nice to meet…
我的天
Oh! My god!
什么情况
What the hell is this?
星期五 他们在朝什么开火
Friday, what are they firing at?
有东西穿过了大气层
Something just entered the upper atmosphere.
来了
Oh, yeah!
丹佛斯 我们需要支援
Danvers, we need an assist here.
你好 我是彼得·帕克
Hi. I'm Peter Parker.
你好 彼得·帕克 你有东西要给我吗
Hey, Peter Parker. You got something for me?
你一个人能搞定吗
I don't know how you're gonna get through all that.
别担心
Don't worry.
她不是一个人
She's got help.
我就是 天命
I am… Inevitable.
我
And I…
是
Am…
钢铁侠
Iron man.
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
嘿
Hey…
史塔克先生 能听到我说话吗
Mr. Stark? can you hear me?
我是彼得
It's Peter.
我们赢了
We won.
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark….
我们赢了 史塔克先生
We won, Mr. Stark.
我们赢了 您做到了 先生您做到了
We won and you did it, sir. You did it.
对不起 托尼
I'm sorry… Tony…
- 嘿 - 嘿 佩珀
- Hey. - Hey, pep…
- 星期五 - 生命垂危
- Friday? - Life functions critical.
托尼
Tony.
看着我
Look at me.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be Okay.
你可以休息了
You can rest now.
大家都渴望美好的结局 对吧
Everybody wants a happy ending, right?
但现实并不能尽如人意
But it doesn't always roll that way.
可能这次就不能
Maybe this time.
我希望你们看这个的时候
I'm hoping if you play this back,
是在庆祝
It's in celebration.
我希望家人都再次团聚
I hope families are reunited,
我希望一切复若以往
I hope we get it back, and something like a…
希望这个星球能重新读档
Normal version of the planet has been restored.
如果有存档的话
If there ever was such a thing.
那这个世界该有多美好
God what a world…
还有整个宇宙
Universe now…
如果在十年前你告诉我 我们在这个宇宙当中并不孤单
If you told me ten years ago that we weren't alone…
更不用提接下来发生的这些事情
Let alone you know to this extent…
我可能就不会表现的这样大惊小怪了
I mean, I wouldn't have been surprised…
但是 这种事情又有谁能预料到呢
But come on who knows…
光明和黑暗的力量
That epic forces of darkness and…
都已经现身了
Light that have come and play…
不管结果是好是坏
And for better or worse…
这些都是摩根长大以后
That's the reality morgan's gonna…
需要去面对和探索的现实了
Have to find a way to grow up in…
所以我找时间提前录下来这些
So I found the time and I recorded a little greeting…
以免我不幸身亡
In the case of an untimely death on my part…
对我来说 死亡不是什么意外的事情
Not that death in any time isn't untimely…
明天我们将要进行的
This time travel thing that we're…
时光穿梭
Gonna try…
还真的让我担心我最后能不能活下来
It's, it's got me scratching my head about the survival thing.
但是话说回来 这些都是英雄的使命
But then again, that's the hero gig…
辉煌过后英雄终将落幕
Part of the jourry is the end.
我又何必在这里庸人自扰呢
What am I troubling for Everything's gonna work out…
万事万物自有其道
Exactly the way is supposed to…
摩根 我爱你三千遍
I love you 3, 000.
你知道吗 我真希望
You know, I wish there was a way…
能让她知道
That I could let her know…
我们赢了
That we won…
我们成功了
We did it…
她会知道的
She knows…
他们两个都会知道的
They both do…
你现在怎么样 小可爱
How you doing squirt…
- 我还好 - 你没事吗
- Good - You good…
好 你饿吗
Okay you hungry…
- 你想吃什么 - 芝士汉堡
- What do you want - Cheeseburgers…
知道吗 你爸爸也喜欢吃芝士汉堡
You know your dad liked cheeseburgers…
你想要多少芝士汉堡 我都会给你
I'm gonna get you all the cheeseburgers you want…
好
Okay…
所以 你打算什么时候回来
So when can we expect you back…
- 这个嘛 - 索尔 你的人民需要一个国王
- About that - Thor. Your people need a king…
不 他们已经有了
No they already have one…
别闹了
That's funny…
你是认真的吗
You're being serious…
现在我要去做自己想做的事了
It's time for me to be who I am rather than…
而不是那些我不得不做的事
Who I'm supposed to be…
但是你不同 你天生就是个领导者 这才是真正的你
But you you're a leader that's who you are…
你要知道我可能会让这里变得很不一样
You know I'd make a lot of changes around here…
我很期待 女王陛下
I'm counting on it your majesty…
你打算去做什么
What will you do…
还不知道
I'm not sure…
我这是一千年以来第一次
For the first time in a thousand years i…
我不知道要去哪 但是我可以搭个便车
I have no path I do have a ride though…
再不走就不等你了 胖子
Move it or lose it hairbag…
好啦 我们走吧
Well here we are…
小树苗 真高兴再见到你
Tree good to see you…
啊
Well…
银河阿斯加德护卫队又团聚了
The as-guardians of the galaxy back together again…
我们一会儿先去哪
Where to first…
我先声明一下 这还是我的飞船 我说了算
Just so you know this is my ship still I'm in charge…
我知道 我知道 当然是你说了算
I know I know of course you are…
当然
Of course…
你看 你嘴上说了当然 但是你还是在按地图
See, you say of course, but then you touch the map.
这让我觉得你
It makes you think that maybe you…
并没有意识到这是我的地盘
Didn't realize that I was in charge…
龟儿 这是因为你缺乏安全感 好吗
Quail that's your own insecurities in there Okay…
我只是想做好协助和服务的工作而已
I'm merely trying to be of service as an assistant.
- 是奎尔 - 我就是说的这个
- Quill - That's what I said…
你们两个应该打一架 谁赢了谁说了算
You should fight one another for the honor of leadership…
这主意不错
Sounds fair…
我看没这个必要吧
It's not necessary…
没这个必要 同意
It's not Okay…
我有枪 还是你们想用刀
I got some blasters unless you guys wanna use knives…
太棒了 一定要用刀
Oh yes please use knives…
对 用刀
Yeah knives…
我是格鲁特
I am groot…
没有必要
Not necessary…
我们谁也不用捅谁
There shall be no knifing one another…
所有人都知道谁说了算
Everybody knows who's in charge…
是我
Me…
I am…
是你 当然是你了
Yes you of course…
当然 肯定的
Of course of course…
你要记住
Remember…
你必须把宝石送回到
You have to return the stones at…
你拿到他们的准确时刻
The exact moment you got them…
否则就会出现
Or you're gonna open up a bunch…
一大堆麻烦的多重现实
Of nasty alternaan…
布鲁斯 别担心 我都会搞定的
Don't worry bruce clip all the branches…
你知道吗 我尝试过
You know I tried…
我戴上手套使用宝石的时候
When I had the gauntlet with the stones,
我真的很想把她带回来
I really tried to bring her back…
- 我很想她 - 我也是
- I miss her man - Me too…
如果需要的话 我可以和你一起去
You know if you want I can come with you…
谢谢你 山姆
You're a good man sam…
这次还是我来吧
This one's on me though…
我回来前别做傻事
Don't do anything stupid 'till I get back…
我怎么会 你已经把傻事都做完了
How can I you're taking all the stupid with you…
我会想你的 兄弟
Gonna miss you buddy…
放心吧 巴基
It's gonna be Okay buck…
大概多长时间
How long is this gonna take…
对他来说 他想用多长时间都可以 对我们来说 五秒钟
For him as long as he needs for us five seconds…
队长 准备好了吗
Ready cap…
好 我们会在这里等你
Alright we'll meet you back here Okay…
没问题
You bet…
启动量子领域 三 二 一
Going quantum three two one…
准备返航 五 四 三 二 一
And returning in five four three two one…
他去哪了
Where is he…
我怎么知道 我们把他的时间戳已经同步了 他应该在这里的
I don't know. He blew right by his time step he should be here…
- 那把他弄回来啊 - 我在试了
- Well get him back - I'm trying…
- 快把他带回来 - 我说了我在试了
- Get him the hell back - I said I'm trying…
山姆
Sam.
过去吧
Go ahead…
队长
Cap…
你好啊 山姆
Hi sam…
所以是什么东西出了差错 还是你本意如此
So did something go wrong or did something go right…
把宝石都还回去之后我想
Well, after I put the stones back I thought…
也许我可以尝试一下
Maybe I'll try some of that life tony was…
托尼劝我去过的那种人生
Telling me to get…
过得怎么样
How did that work out for you…
很美好
It was beautiful…
我真为你高兴 真的
I'm happy for you truly…
谢谢
Thank you…
唯一让我感到难过的是
Only thing bumming me out is the fact I have…
我必须要在一个没有美国队长的世界里生活了
To live in a world without captain america…
哦
Oh…
你提醒我了
That reminds me…
戴上试试看
Try it on…
感觉怎么样
How's it feel…
感觉好像是别人的
Like it's someone else's…
这是你的
It isn't…
谢谢你
Thank you…
我会尽力的
I'll do my best…
所以这属于你了
That's why it's yours…
你想跟我聊聊她吗
You wanna tell me about her…
不
No…
我可能不会
No I don't think I will.